<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ecobee Switch+ on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/ecobee-switch+/</link><description>Recent content in ecobee Switch+ on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 19:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/ecobee-switch+/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disturbing trends in smart home products and services</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/disturbing-trends-in-smart-home-products-and-services/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 19:45:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/disturbing-trends-in-smart-home-products-and-services/</guid><description>Over the last decade there has been some really great software products that have been shut down with little to no warning. This is getting so common that someone created a website called Killed by Google. After Google shutdown Reader in 2013, I spent months trying to find a replacement. During this research I determined I should try to find solutions to services I use everyday that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be shut down in some board room over profit margins.</description></item><item><title>How-to normalize home volume levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>This post is going to cover normalizing all media_player volume levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend reading my previous blog post on sending Text-to-Speech notifications which dives a bit deeper on the optional accessibility Subflow this Flow consumes.
This automation normalizes all volume levels in my home based on the time of day using the Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to bring in all my Amazon Echo and ecobee Switch+ devices into Home Assistant.</description></item><item><title>How-to send Text-to-Speech notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:35:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to send Text-to-Speech (TTS) notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED? In the sections below I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to send TTS notifications. Please note you can easily switch out the TTS integration to the one of your choosing and still use this Subflow (with a few tweaks).
This is one of my favorite Subflows as it can be used easily in a lot of automations.</description></item><item><title>Let's talk about smart home accessibility</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</guid><description>I define accessibility as a critical necessity to be inclusive to everyone. No matter how big or small the task, anyone should be able complete the task at hand regardless of the disability (e.g., vision, hearing, mobility, device access, language, etc).
You might be wondering what does this have to do with smart homes and why should I think or care about this? I think there are a few simple facts to consider:</description></item></channel></rss>