<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Z-Wave on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/z-wave/</link><description>Recent content in Z-Wave on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/z-wave/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let's talk about smart home accessibility</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</guid><description>I define accessibility as a critical necessity to be inclusive to everyone. No matter how big or small the task, anyone should be able complete the task at hand regardless of the disability (e.g., vision, hearing, mobility, device access, language, etc).
You might be wondering what does this have to do with smart homes and why should I think or care about this? I think there are a few simple facts to consider:</description></item><item><title>Installing Home Assistant on Ubuntu</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 02:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>I recently upgraded my Home Assistant server to an Intel NUC 10 Performance Kit (NUC10i7FNH) from an Atomic Pi. I needed to manually install and configure Ubuntu on my hardware there is an issue where you cannot boot from the NVMe drive. and I wanted more control over secondary storage and services.
If you are looking for hardware recommendations to run Home Assistant or a small server on please check out Upgrading Home Assistant Hardware.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Home Assistant hardware in 2020</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded or swapped my Home Assistant hardware more times than I want to count. I want to share the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way when choosing hardware to run Home Assistant locally. I always try choose hardware is lower power and will take up limited space in my 9U Server Cabinet
Skip to March 2020 for a summary of what I recently upgraded to and the Conclusion if you are looking for current hardware recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about smart home power usage</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a great deal of my life admiring nature and thinking of ways we can do to reduce our footprint. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve taken steps both physically and monetarily to do so.
The Dreaded Power Bill Which is why one Wisconsin Winter day I opened my utility (gas and electric) bill and had a not so pleasant moment. Complete sticker shock at the $410 USD single month total, which was our highest bill yet.</description></item><item><title>Hello Home Automation, How-to detect battery levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start off 2020 by converting my blog to Hugo and start blogging again! This is my first of many posts on home automation! This post is going to cover generically detecting battery levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED.
TLDR: Use the Function node defined in the Node-RED snippet here to properly handle all the edge cases.
I decided to share my experiences based on seeing what others were doing in this thread.</description></item></channel></rss>