<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 11:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A lesson in Color Theory for Developers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/programming/a-lesson-in-color-theory-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/programming/a-lesson-in-color-theory-for-developers/</guid><description>I read this article the other day and it struck me how often this happens. As a developer I sometimes find it hard to create even a decent looking GUI. Most of the time when developers through together a GUI it has 60 million check boxes on it and it does not look visually pleasing.
Color theory may sound like a subject for the Art Department, not for developers. But we&amp;rsquo;ve all had the experience of choosing a color scheme using the property grid to select named colors and ending up with a really garish color scheme.</description></item><item><title>A white paper on how to make your Windows Vista application UAC friendly.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/programming/a-white-paper-on-how-to-make-your-windows-vista-application-uac-friendly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/programming/a-white-paper-on-how-to-make-your-windows-vista-application-uac-friendly/</guid><description>Microsoft has released a white paper pertaining on &amp;ldquo;how to develop UAC compliant applications for Windows Vista&amp;rdquo;, The following document contains the subjects or topics below.
This white paper includes details many aspects of designing and building applications that will work well with User Account Control (UAC) on Windows Vista.
At a high level, it describes the following steps to use when designing applications for Windows Vista:
Test Your Application for Application Compatibility Classify Your Application as a Standard User, Administrator, or Mixed User Application Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s Functionality for UAC Compatibility Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s User Interface for UAC Compatibility Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s Installer Create and Embed an Application Manifest with Your Application Test Your Application Authenticode Sign Your Application Participate in the Windows Vista Logo Program In addition, it describes some interesting setup-specific considerations.</description></item></channel></rss>