<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/</link><description>Recent content on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading Home Assistant hardware in 2020</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded or swapped my Home Assistant hardware more times than I want to count. I want to share the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way when choosing hardware to run Home Assistant locally. I always try choose hardware is lower power and will take up limited space in my 9U Server Cabinet
Skip to March 2020 for a summary of what I recently upgraded to and the Conclusion if you are looking for current hardware recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about smart home power usage</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a great deal of my life admiring nature and thinking of ways we can do to reduce our footprint. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve taken steps both physically and monetarily to do so.
The Dreaded Power Bill Which is why one Wisconsin Winter day I opened my utility (gas and electric) bill and had a not so pleasant moment. Complete sticker shock at the $410 USD single month total, which was our highest bill yet.</description></item><item><title>Hello Home Automation, How to detect battery levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start off 2020 by converting my blog to Hugo and start blogging again! This is my first of many posts on home automation! This post is going to cover generically detecting battery levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED.
TLDR: Use the Function node defined in the Node-RED snippet here to properly handle all the edge cases.
I decided to share my experiences based on seeing what others were doing in this thread.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at BAM</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-bam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-bam/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at From BAM-Big Data, Advanced Analytics, Machine Learning Scaling Your Applications and Skill Set on January 15th!
Overview Blake will lead a discussion regarding the struggles around starting and using open source projects to build software solutions for customers. Going from having no customers, to doing 3+ billion requests per month in Azure was a sometimes painful experience, especially on a limited budget. Blake will discuss what he has learned, as well as talk about data acquisition and maintenance, and talk about problems working with large data sets.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Central Wisconsin It Conference</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-central-wisconsin-it-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-central-wisconsin-it-conference/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at Central Wisconsin IT Conference on Exception Driven Development on October 6th!
Overview What is &amp;ldquo;Exception Driven Development&amp;rdquo;? If customer-facing issues are your top priority, then you already adhere to the primary principle of Exception Driven Development.
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple concept: Collect application data, especially regarding errors and crashes, and then focus on fixing those problems that your users are actually experiencing. Join me for 60 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong with your current log collection approach, and how you should be doing it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Northeast Wisconsin Code Camp</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-northeast-wisconsin-code-camp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-northeast-wisconsin-code-camp/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at Northeast Wisconsin Code Camp on Exception Driven Development on March 24th!!
Overview What is &amp;ldquo;Exception Driven Development&amp;rdquo;? If customer-facing issues are your top priority, then you already adhere to the primary principle of Exception Driven Development.
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple concept: Collect application data, especially regarding errors and crashes, and then focus on fixing those problems that your users are actually experiencing. Join me for 60 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong with your current log collection approach, and how you should be doing it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Milwaukee Code Camp</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-milwaukee-code-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-milwaukee-code-camp/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at Milwaukee Code Camp on Exception Driven Development on November 11, 2017
Overview What is &amp;ldquo;Exception Driven Development&amp;rdquo;? If customer-facing issues are your top priority, then you already adhere to the primary principle of Exception Driven Development.
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple concept: Collect application data, especially regarding errors and crashes, and then focus on fixing those problems that your users are actually experiencing. Join me for 60 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong with your current log collection approach, and how you should be doing it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at North Dallas .NET User Group</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-north-dallas-net-user-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-north-dallas-net-user-group/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at North Dallas .NET User Group on Exception Driven Development on November 11, 2017
Overview What is &amp;ldquo;Exception Driven Development&amp;rdquo;? If customer-facing issues are your top priority, then you already adhere to the primary principle of Exception Driven Development.
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple concept: Collect application data, especially regarding errors and crashes, and then focus on fixing those problems that your users are actually experiencing. Join me for 60 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong with your current log collection approach, and how you should be doing it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Milwaukee .NET Conference</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-milwaukee-net-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-milwaukee-net-conference/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at Milwaukee .NET Conference on Exception Driven Development on November 11, 2017
Overview What is &amp;ldquo;Exception Driven Development&amp;rdquo;? If customer-facing issues are your top priority, then you already adhere to the primary principle of Exception Driven Development.
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple concept: Collect application data, especially regarding errors and crashes, and then focus on fixing those problems that your users are actually experiencing. Join me for 60 minutes and I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what you&amp;rsquo;re doing wrong with your current log collection approach, and how you should be doing it.</description></item><item><title>The best JavaScript IDE</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-best-javascript-ide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 14:47:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-best-javascript-ide/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I was asked to write a review by WebStorm for a free open source license. With that said you will always get my honest feedback about the pros and cons about these editors.
About a month ago I started writing the new AngularJS based spa app for Exceptionless 2.0. While learning about AngularJS I looked around and used several editors to see which one worked the best. I&amp;rsquo;ll break down the editors that I used and conclude which one I liked the best.</description></item><item><title>Exceptionless Goes Open Source</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/exceptionless-goes-open-source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 13:33:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/exceptionless-goes-open-source/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a big day at Exceptionless. We are super excited to announce that we are open sourcing the Exceptionless code! That&amp;rsquo;s right, now you can hack on our real-time error reporting tool yourself.
Too many apps are throwing too many errors out there, resulting in confused users, lost business, and endless frustration.
We believe Exceptionless can help the development community become more in-tune with their code by making those errors more transparent, trackable, and squashable.</description></item><item><title>How-to open a Visual Studio Document Window using the Visual Studio API</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-open-a-visual-studio-document-window-using-the-visual-studio-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 20:24:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-open-a-visual-studio-document-window-using-the-visual-studio-api/</guid><description>I had spent considerable time trying to open a new document window and then set the document text to the result of the generated template text. I found this to be an almost impossible task and proposed this on the Microsoft Visual Studio Extensibility forums. The response that I got was that after looking into this functionality the best approach would be to save the text to a file and then open the document window.</description></item><item><title>Implementing GoTo Line functionality in a Visual Studio Custom Editor</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/implementing-goto-line-functionality-in-a-visual-studio-custom-editor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 19:15:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/implementing-goto-line-functionality-in-a-visual-studio-custom-editor/</guid><description>While implementing a custom CodeSmith Generator Template Editor into Visual Studio 2010. I ran into an issue with getting the GoTo Line functionality to work properly. According to Microsoft this functionality needs to be provided by the custom editor as well as the GoTo Line dialog will need to be implemented as there is no &amp;ldquo;official public extension point&amp;rdquo;. This makes sense if you are taking over control of the editor but I feel that Microsoft should expose this dialog.</description></item><item><title>Announcing The CodeSmith Generator 6.0 Visual Studio Template Editor</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/announcing-the-codesmith-generator-6.0-visual-studio-template-editor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 18:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/announcing-the-codesmith-generator-6.0-visual-studio-template-editor/</guid><description>We are very excited to announce that CodeSmith Generator 6.0 will feature a built-in Visual Studio CodeSmith Generator Template Editor on top of our existing Visual Studio Integration. The team has been hard at work integrating a new Template Editor into our Visual Studio integration story. Without further ado:
As you can see from the screenshot above, the CodeSmith Generator Template Editor is sitting inside of Visual Studio. This means you can use a familiar Development Interface to develop, edit and generate templates.</description></item><item><title>Extending the CodeSmith Generator PLINQO templates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/extending-the-codesmith-generator-plinqo-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 03:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/extending-the-codesmith-generator-plinqo-templates/</guid><description>The following guide will walk you through the basics on how-to extend the CodeSmith Generator PLINQO Templates to fit your custom development needs. In this example we will create a new Webpage for each entity that we generate. This page will contain a LinqDataSource control and an ASP.NET GridView control that will display data from a corresponding entity that we generated. I always recommend that you use the PLINQO API when writing templates that interact with code generated by PLINQO as this ensures that the code generated has the proper names and associations and or types.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Create a new Oracle User</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-create-a-new-oracle-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 13:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-create-a-new-oracle-user/</guid><description>Every now and then I need to create a new Oracle user to test the CodeSmith Generator OracleSchemaProvider. I wanted to outline the steps that I use to create a new user as well as change the password of an existing user.
The first step one needs to take is to create a new user but you may not remember your login information if it has been a while. At this point I always open up SQL Plus from the start menu and enter in the following user name when prompted.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Windows SharePoint Services 3.0: Software Development Kit (SDK)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-sharepoint-services-3.0-software-development-kit-sdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 17:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-sharepoint-services-3.0-software-development-kit-sdk/</guid><description>The Windows SharePoint Services 3.0 software development kit (SDK) has been released and contains conceptual overviews, programming tasks, samples, and references to guide you in developing solutions based on Microsoft Windows SharePoint Services 3.0.
Source Microsoft</description></item><item><title>Beginning Silverlight 4 in C#</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/beginning-silverlight-4-in-csharp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/beginning-silverlight-4-in-csharp/</guid><description>I have read many technical books over the years and this is one is one of those books that you know you better keep handy. I really like how Robert has this book laid out and how he introduces you to Silverlight. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a .NET guy since version 1.0. But like most developers, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to really dive into Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s latest technologies like Silverlight until they have a few versions released.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Use a Stored Procedure extended property to preserve custom logic in generated CSLA code.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-a-stored-procedure-extended-property-to-preserve-custom-logic-in-generated-csla-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-a-stored-procedure-extended-property-to-preserve-custom-logic-in-generated-csla-code/</guid><description>In the previous article on how to use the partial methods in the CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates to preserve custom code mostly focused on the code side of things. For those of you who might be using Stored Procedures might be wondering&amp;hellip; How do I accomplish preserving my custom stored procedure logic? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, CodeSmith already though of this and didn&amp;rsquo;t leave you out in the dark! The CSLA templates by default will not automatically execute the generated stored procedures but it can!</description></item><item><title>How-to: Use partial methods to preserve custom CSLA code and promote active regeneration.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-partial-methods-to-preserve-custom-csla-code-and-promote-active-regeneration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-partial-methods-to-preserve-custom-csla-code-and-promote-active-regeneration/</guid><description>One of the best features of code generation is the reality of being able to actively generate you code while preserving custom changes. This allows you to implement custom logic while constantly making changes to your metadata and getting the latest template changes. CodeSmith Generator has worked hard on making this happen in both the PLINQO and CSLA Templates. The CSLA templates offer many partial method overrides to make your life easier.</description></item><item><title>Breaking CSLA 4.0 property changes when using private backing fields.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/breaking-csla-4.0-property-changes-when-using-private-backing-fields/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/breaking-csla-4.0-property-changes-when-using-private-backing-fields/</guid><description>I came across this bug last night, which was occurring right as CSLA 4 was released. It had to deal with the CodeSmith CSLA templates when you set UseMemberVariables to true. The error is quite obscure and not very intuitive as the signs of a bug are only found when you check to see if your business object IsValid. The scenario in this case is when you set a required managed property, the rules never fully evaluate the set value.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Preserve column names in generated PLINQO entities</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-preserve-column-names-in-generated-plinqo-entities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-preserve-column-names-in-generated-plinqo-entities/</guid><description>There may come a time where you need to rename a column in your generated entity for whatever reason. The following tip and trick article will show you how to quickly accomplish this.
Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you have a generated property for the column AccountId and it is defined like this:
[System.CodeDom.Compiler.GeneratedCode(&amp;#34;CodeSmith&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;5.0.0.0&amp;#34;)] private int _accountId = default(int); /// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt; /// Gets the AccountId column value. /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt; [System.Data.Linq.Mapping.Column(Name = &amp;#34;AccountId&amp;#34;, Storage = &amp;#34;_accountId&amp;#34;, DbType = &amp;#34;int NOT NULL IDENTITY&amp;#34;, IsPrimaryKey = true, IsDbGenerated = true, CanBeNull = false)] [System.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Upgrade a Community Server website thats running 2.1, 2007 or 2008 site to Community Server 2008 or Telligent Community 5.5</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-a-community-server-website-thats-running-2.1-2007-or-2008-site-to-community-server-2008-or-telligent-community-5.5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-a-community-server-website-thats-running-2.1-2007-or-2008-site-to-community-server-2008-or-telligent-community-5.5/</guid><description>I have done a few of these upgrades for a few big sites like bink.nu and Sober.com. Here is the safest way without a ton of headaches. Please contact me if you need help, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to do the upgrade for people as well&amp;hellip; Please do SQL backups after every step!
Database Instructions Upgrade from Community Server 2.1 to 2007.0 Create a SQL backup. Run SQL Compare against a fresh database of cs2007 to the upgraded database and make sure everything transferred correctly.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator supports Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 RTM!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-supports-microsoft-visual-studio-2010-rtm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 07:59:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-supports-microsoft-visual-studio-2010-rtm/</guid><description>We have been working with Microsoft over the past few months to ensure that CodeSmith Generator works with Microsoft Visual Studio 2010. The currently released version of CodeSmith Generator 5.x already supports Visual Studio 2010 Integration. Although the current support is titled as beta we have ran into very few Visual Studio 2010 bugs and will completely stand behind Visual Studio 2010.
Microsoft and Microsoft logo&amp;rsquo;s are trademarks of Microsoft Corporation.</description></item><item><title>Unit testing the CodeSmith Generator CSLA generated template code</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/unit-testing-the-codesmith-generator-csla-generated-template-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 10:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/unit-testing-the-codesmith-generator-csla-generated-template-code/</guid><description>During the development of our CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates we have spent a lot time unit testing the generated code to ensure everything was working correctly.
In the future we would like to generate basic CRUD unit tests for any project. We decided to unit test the PetShop database to go along with our PetShop Sample application. We have a solution both in VB and C# that can be found in (Documents\CodeSmith\Samples\v5.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Upgrade your existing PLINQO or CSLA CodeSmith Generator Templates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-plinqo-or-csla-codesmith-generator-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 02:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-plinqo-or-csla-codesmith-generator-templates/</guid><description>This article will help you upgrade your solutions templates safely and easily to the latest major or minor version. The latest templates can be found on our repository and the latest nightly build can be found here. The first thing to do is to download the template framework you wish to update.
After the templates have been downloaded and extracted. Remove or Replace the old templates with the new ones keeping the same folder structure or simply update your CodeSmith Generator Project File(s) to point to the updated templates.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Use Microsoft SQL Server CLR Functions and Functions in your CodeSmith Generator Templates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-sql-server-clr-functions-and-functions-in-your-codesmith-generator-templates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 21:44:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-sql-server-clr-functions-and-functions-in-your-codesmith-generator-templates/</guid><description>In a previousarticle, I had mentioned that we added support for Microsoft SQL Server CLR Stored procedures and Functionsin the release of CodeSmith Generator 5.2. Since then there has been a few questions since then on how to add this to your existing templates. The great news is, you can add the functionality in a few easy changes.
To enable SQL function support you need to set IncludeFunctions=&amp;quot;True&amp;quot; on any types inheriting from SchemaObjectBase (E.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Use Microsoft SQL Server Functions in your CodeSmith Generator Templates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-sql-server-functions-in-your-codesmith-generator-templates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 21:51:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-sql-server-functions-in-your-codesmith-generator-templates/</guid><description>CodeSmith Generator now supports Microsoft SQL ServerFunctions and Microsoft SQL Server CLR Functions with the release of CodeSmith Generator 5.2. I will quickly show you how to add Microsoft SQL Server Function support to your CodeSmith Generator template.
The first thing you need to do in order to use SQL Functions is to set the IncludeFunctions Property on any type that derives from SchemaObjectBase. The following property types are capable of showing functions when you add the IncludeFunctions=&amp;quot;True&amp;quot; setting to the property: CommandSchema, CommandSchemaCollection and DatabaseSchema.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Build a custom UITypeEditor</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-build-a-custom-uitypeeditor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-build-a-custom-uitypeeditor/</guid><description>Recently, I built a CodeSmith Generator sample UITypeEditor that allows a user to enter in custom data into a DropDownList. In the following article I&amp;rsquo;ll show you what you need to do in order to build your own UITypeEditor. First you need to create a public class that will hold the data of the drop down list. In this example I named my class DropDownListProperty.
public class DropDownListProperty { } Next we will need to add the properties and the constructors.</description></item><item><title>It's the littlest of things that we do, that make CodeSmith Generator shine.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/its-the-littlest-of-things-that-we-do-that-make-codesmith-generator-shine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 07:25:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/its-the-littlest-of-things-that-we-do-that-make-codesmith-generator-shine/</guid><description>During each release of CodeSmith Generator, one thing we always do is test upgrade scenarios between each versions and check for backwards compatibility among other tests. Recently, I was amazed at how much change has taken place between CodeSmith Generator 4.x and the latest CodeSmith Generator 5.1.x release when it comes to the user interface. CodeSmith Generator has made a huge effort to make CodeSmith Generator rock solid, crazy fast, and easy to use.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator CSLA Templates v1.0 released!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-v1.0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 05:40:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-v1.0-released/</guid><description>Over a week ago we released our new CodeSmith Generator CSLA Templates. I highly recommend everyone that uses CSLA to try them out as they will save you a ton of time. Also you&amp;rsquo;ll notice very quickly that it follows the CSLA best practices and has other features that you have been looking for like a working Data Access Layer (DAL). The best part is that you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about learning something new (the generated code) if you are already familiar with the CSLA Framework.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Debugging CodeSmith Generator on Microsoft Windows 7</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-debugging-codesmith-generator-on-microsoft-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 03:46:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-debugging-codesmith-generator-on-microsoft-windows-7/</guid><description>We have updated the Tips &amp;amp; Tricks: Debugging CodeSmith Generator with the changes needed to debug CodeSmith Generator on Microsoft Windows 7.
Here is the quick overview of what you need to-do to enable debugging on a Microsoft Windows 7 machine.
Update the Just-In-Time debugger setting DbgJITDebugLaunchSetting. The setting is found in the registry at HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\.NETFramework. Set the value of DbgJITDebugLaunchSetting to 2. If you are using a 64bit operating system then you must also set the same key DbgJITDebugLaunchSetting in this folder HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Wow6432Node\Microsoft\.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator CSLA Templates Part 2: The Quick Start</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-part-2-the-quick-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-part-2-the-quick-start/</guid><description>In Part 1: The Introduction was an overview of the CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates we are developing at CodeSmith. In this post, I am going to go over how to use the CSLA quick start and the new improvements resulting from customer feedback (Keep the feedback coming!).
First launch CodeSmith Generator Studio and under the Frameworks node open the CSLA Folder.
There are a couple of folders in the CodeSmith.CSLA folder</description></item><item><title>A fix for the Microsoft .Net Framework 3.5 SP1 Fatal Execution Error (VS Silent Death Bug).</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-fix-for-the-microsoft-.net-framework-3.5-sp1-fatal-execution-error-vs-silent-death-bug/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-fix-for-the-microsoft-.net-framework-3.5-sp1-fatal-execution-error-vs-silent-death-bug/</guid><description>We released CodeSmith Generator 5.1 with the new requirements of the Microsoft .Net Framework 3.5. One of our experiences in upgrading to the .Net Framework 3.5 is issues we have run into like our customers reporting Visual Studio disappearing or closing extremely quick when they try to generate code using CodeSmith&amp;rsquo;s Visual Studio Integration. The following link Tools - Part 11 - Add-ins - Attempting to work around the &amp;ldquo;VS Silent Death&amp;rdquo; bug describes this issue in detail.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Register a keyboard shortcut (hot key) in a .NET Windows Forms Application.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-register-a-keyboard-shortcut-hot-key-in-a-.net-windows-forms-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-register-a-keyboard-shortcut-hot-key-in-a-.net-windows-forms-application/</guid><description>There may come a time when you want to implement some extra features or maybe an Easter egg into your application using keyboard shortcuts. I was recently tasked with creating an Easter egg so we could test some functionality in CodeSmith. After countless searches looking for an elegant solution (I found a few ugly solutions and some nicer ones) I came across Method #3. I&amp;rsquo;ll First touch on the one I didn&amp;rsquo;t choose to go with.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 Beta 1 is coming to MSDN on May 18th.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2010-beta-1-is-coming-to-msdn-on-may-18th/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 07:24:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2010-beta-1-is-coming-to-msdn-on-may-18th/</guid><description>So far I have been very impressed with the CTP builds of Microsoft Visual Studio 2010. There are some really welcoming changes that are apart of Visual Studio 2010 like UI Unit tests and a completely new IDE written in WPF. The only area where I thought was lacking was the responsiveness of the application. Last night a few members of the Visual Studio team announced that one of there main goals for Beta 1 and RTM is on Performance.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Protect your Telligent Community website from spammers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-telligent-community-website-from-spammers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-telligent-community-website-from-spammers/</guid><description>One should always be aware that your site could be attacked by spam bots if you don&amp;rsquo;t take the proper precautions. The easiest and quickest way to help prevent 500+ spam users from joining your site is to configure the default options to make it harder for spam bots to create accounts. Please note that this can also reduce the number of registrations on your site due to the extra steps it takes to register.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Protect your Telligent Community website from rouge spiders with a robots text file</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-telligent-community-website-from-rouge-spiders-with-a-robots-text-file/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-telligent-community-website-from-rouge-spiders-with-a-robots-text-file/</guid><description>Over the course of the past two years, I have worked on a number of Community Server sites. The goal of these tips are to share useful information about Telligent&amp;rsquo;s Community platform. There are a few ways you can protect yourself from rouge search bots from stealing your content and bringing down your site.
The easiest way is to setup a robots text file, which will tell search engines to ignore certain files or directories.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator 5.1 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-5.1-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 21:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-5.1-released/</guid><description>On May 6th we released CodeSmith Generator 5.1. This update brings in many welcoming changes, to name a few: .netTiers 2.3, PLINQO 3.0. Also CodeSmith Generator and now requires that the .NET 3.5 Framework is installed before CodeSmith Generator installs.
Final Updated installer to launch CodeSmith Generator after install. Loading a CSP on a new machine with an new connection string will cause TableSchema&amp;rsquo;s UI to be blank. Fixed a bug where removing a data source from Database Explorer wouldn&amp;rsquo;t permanently remove the data source.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Open a mini dump file (mdmp) with WinDbg</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-open-a-mini-dump-file-mdmp-with-windbg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 13:41:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-open-a-mini-dump-file-mdmp-with-windbg/</guid><description>Today I was debugging an issue where Microsoft Visual Studio was closing at random in a Microsoft Visual Studio Package. We narrowed down the issue to a previous Microsoft bug report. I came to a point where Microsoft Visual Studio was creating a mini dump file.
After some quick thinking, I downloaded and installed Debugging Tools for Windows. I then opened WinDbg and clicked on Open Crash Dump and navigated to the location above.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Clear cached contacts from Microsoft Outlook</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-clear-cached-contacts-from-microsoft-outlook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-clear-cached-contacts-from-microsoft-outlook/</guid><description>A long time ago we needed a script to remove the cached contacts in Microsoft Outlook. After some research we found that these were stored in a NK2 file in the user profile directory. To run the script please close Outlook and create a new batch file (text file with the extension of .bat), or download the file below.
Please not this will create a backup of the NK2 file so everything can be reverted.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator CSLA Templates Part 1: The Introduction</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-part-1-the-introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 08:46:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-csla-templates-part-1-the-introduction/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the CodeSmith Generator CSLA Templates periodically over the past few months at CodeSmith Tools. We have designed the templates from the ground up around the CSLA.NET Framework version 3.6.2. You might be thinking what&amp;rsquo;s the big deal it&amp;rsquo;s just another set of CSLA templates. You are mistaken, we have done a lot of research and gathered a lot of feedback. The end result is a streamlined CSLA experience that is highly customizable.</description></item><item><title>.netTiers 2.3.0 Beta 2 Released!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/nettiers-2.3.0-beta-2-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 11:13:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/nettiers-2.3.0-beta-2-released/</guid><description>The .netTiers team released .netTiers 2.3.0 Beta 2 today. .netTiers 2.3.0 is a maintenance release containing many bug fixes and patches. We have also added various requested features like Enterprise Library version 4.1 as well as support for Visual Studio 2008. I would have to say the biggest and most requested feature that went into .netTiers 2.3.0 Beta 2 was support for Oracle!
Here is a list of all the changes since .</description></item><item><title>How-to: Connect to an Oracle Database with CodeSmith Generator</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-connect-to-an-oracle-database-with-codesmith-generator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 03:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-connect-to-an-oracle-database-with-codesmith-generator/</guid><description>Sometimes User interfaces can&amp;rsquo;t provide a solution for every scenario where you might need additional functionality by customization. One area where you might come across this is if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to use Oracle on an 64bit machine or in a custom Oracle instance. If you are running Windows XP there is a good chance you can get away with using the built in Connection Editor and use CodeSmith to connect to your Oracle Schema.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Set the File Encoding of an CodeSmith Generator Template</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-set-the-file-encoding-of-an-codesmith-generator-template/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 05:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-set-the-file-encoding-of-an-codesmith-generator-template/</guid><description>There may be a time when you need to use Extended ASCII Codes in your CodeSmith Generator Templates. If you have already tried using them into your template you have more than likely ran into the following problem. When a user first creates a template an Encoding attribute is not added by default to the CodeTemplate directive. So when a user starts adding characters in the Extended ASCII range, they will run into the following problem without first setting the encoding attribute.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008: Cumulative Update 1 (CU1) Now Available</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-cumulative-update-1-cu1-now-available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 07:52:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-cumulative-update-1-cu1-now-available/</guid><description>An update is available for SQL Server 2008. A list of all the fixes can be found here.
Download Cumulative update package 1 for SQL Server 2008</description></item><item><title>Microsoft PDC 2008</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-pdc-2008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 09:07:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-pdc-2008/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sad that I will not be attending Microsoft PDC. There are a lot of interesting sessions this year that sound appealing to me. For a complete list visit the Microsoft PDC 2008 site.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Windows Live Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-live-tools-for-microsoft-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 18:02:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-live-tools-for-microsoft-visual-studio/</guid><description>Windows Live™ Tools for Microsoft® Visual Studio® 2008 are a set of control add-ins to make incorporating Windows Live services into your Web application easier with Visual Studio 2008 and Visual Web Developer Express 2008.
Download the Community Technical Preview of Windows Live Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio Now
The six controls included in this CTP release are: Contacts Control (reference) IDLoginStatus Control (reference)* IDLoginView Control (reference)* MessengerChat Control (reference)* SilverlightStreamingMediaPlayer Control (reference)* Map Control (reference)* Requirements for Using Windows Live Tools This CTP release only targets English (United States).</description></item><item><title>Video: Hug a developer</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-hug-a-developer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 19:54:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-hug-a-developer/</guid><description>I just came across this video and thought I would share it with anyone reading this blog. Hug a developer</description></item><item><title>FxCop 1.36 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/fxcop-1.36-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 19:44:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/fxcop-1.36-released/</guid><description>After a very long time, an Microsoft FxCop update has been released. Here is a list of all that has changed:
200+ bug fixes that reduce noise, missing analysis and rule crashes Support for analyzing anonymous methods and lambda expressions New option for skipping analysis over tool generated code Spell checker libraries now ship in the box Changes in the way references are resolved and located Better support for C++/CLI and the Compact Framework Language &amp;lsquo;friendly&amp;rsquo; API names in the UI and resolutions (ie Visual Basic syntax if running over a Visual Basic binary) New globalization, design and usage rules New rule for targeting specific versions of the Framework Performance improvements that cut analysis by 2x and use half as much memory Documentation that is now available on MSDN Source FxCop 1.</description></item><item><title>ASP.NET MVC Preview 5</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-mvc-preview-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 07:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-mvc-preview-5/</guid><description>This ASP.NET MVC CodePlex Preview 5 is an interim release that contains some new features and some feature improvements for which the ASP.NET MVC team would like to receive feedback from the community. Note: Before you run the ASP.NET MVC CodePlex Preview 5 installer, be sure to uninstall any earlier previews of ASP.NET MVC that you might have installed. In addition, close all instances of Visual Studio 2008.
The following issues are addressed in this release (see the Release Notes for more detail on any changes)</description></item><item><title>How-to: Manual uninstall CodeSmith Generator</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-manual-uninstall-codesmith-generator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 03:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-manual-uninstall-codesmith-generator/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a few issues, where a CodeSmith Generator install might become corrupt when going from a beta to RTM. The following guide will show you how to successfully remove CodeSmith Generator from your computer. Please allow 10 to 15 minutes of your time to complete this guide.
Please note: This guide could be used to uninstall other .net applications.
You will need to download the Windows Installer CleanUp Utility.</description></item><item><title>CodeSmith Generator 5.0 RTM available now</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-5.0-rtm-available-now/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 12:37:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/codesmith-generator-5.0-rtm-available-now/</guid><description>Over the past year the CodeSmith team has been hard at work on CodeSmith Generator 5.0. This release contains many fixes, performance enhancements and other enhancements over the previous versions. Below is a list of some of the major changes between CodeSmith Generator 5.0 and CodeSmith Generator 4.0. I have highlighted some of my favorites below.
5.0.0 Final Added a tab for editing variables in the CodeSmith Project settings dialog.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 SP1 and .NET Framework 3.5 SP1 RTM</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-sp1-and-.net-framework-3.5-sp1-rtm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 08:24:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-sp1-and-.net-framework-3.5-sp1-rtm/</guid><description>I was so happy to see that Microsoft has finally release Visual Studio 2008 SP1 and the .NET Framework 3.5 SP1. It contains so many improvements and bug fixes; you can view the full list of the enhancements at Scott Guthrie&amp;rsquo;s blog.
Unlike other Service Packs from Microsoft, the SP1 of.Net Framework 3.5 and Visual Studio 2008 not only contains bug fixes and improvements, it also contains new technologies such as ADO.</description></item><item><title>Overview of CLR improvements in the .NET Framework 3.5 SP1</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/overview-of-clr-improvements-in-the-.net-framework-3.5-sp1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 18:14:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/overview-of-clr-improvements-in-the-.net-framework-3.5-sp1/</guid><description>Below is a list of all the sweet improvements made to the .NET Framework 3.5 Service Pack 1 since the .NET Framework 3.5 was initially released!
NGen infrastructure rewrite: the new infrastructure uses less memory, produces less fragmented NGen images with much better locality, and does so in dramatically less time. What this means to you: Installing or servicing an NGen image is much faster, and cold startup time of your NGen&amp;rsquo;ed code is better.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the Madison .NET User Group</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-madison.net-user-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-the-madison.net-user-group/</guid><description>Date: Wednesday, July 30, doors open at 5pm Topic: Code Generation Speaker: Blake Niemyjski Location: Herzing College, East Madison Campus, 5218 East Terrace Drive, 53718
Description Blake Niemyjski is a full time student studying Computer Science and Mathematics. His previous studies included RSA Encryption and Number Theory. This coming year he will be attending UW-Madison to continue his education. Since the late 90&amp;rsquo;s Blake has had a curiosity in developing software with the goal of making software that helps the masses accomplish tasks.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft StyleCop: Source Code Analyzer for C# Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-stylecop-source-code-analyzer-for-csharp-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 02:15:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-stylecop-source-code-analyzer-for-csharp-released/</guid><description>Here is a cool internal tool used by Microsoft that is now seeing daylight.
&amp;quot;We are very excited to announce the release of a new developer tool from Microsoft, Source Analysis for C#. This tool is known internally within Microsoft as StyleCop, and has been used for many years now to help teams enforce a common set of best practices for layout, readability, maintainability, and documentation of C# source code.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Install Microsoft Windows Live software on Windows 64bit Operating Systems</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-install-microsoft-windows-live-software-on-windows-64bit-operating-systems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 18:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-install-microsoft-windows-live-software-on-windows-64bit-operating-systems/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that many of you have attempted to download the latest version of Windows Live Messenger or other Windows Live Software but have been prompted with the following error:
Sorry, Windows Live programs cannot be installed on Windows Server, Windows XP Professional x64 Edition, or Windows operating systems earlier than Windows XP Service Pack 2.
You&amp;rsquo;re not alone, as I have received the same error when trying to install the latest version on Windows Server 2008 64bit.</description></item><item><title>.netTiers 2.3.0 Beta 1 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/nettiers-2.3.0-beta-1-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 14:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/nettiers-2.3.0-beta-1-released/</guid><description>The .netTiers team released .netTiers 2.3.0 Beta 1 the other day. .netTiers 2.3.0 is a maintenance release containing many bug fixes and patches. We have also added various requested features like Enterprise Library version 4 as well as support for Visual Studio 2008.
You can download the 2.3.0 Beta 1 templates at the following locations. You can download it the following locations:
repository Please submit all bug reports to the issue tracker.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Reset the CodeSmith Generator Sample Templates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-reset-the-codesmith-generator-sample-templates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 12:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-reset-the-codesmith-generator-sample-templates/</guid><description>A tip that not a lot of people know is that the samples are not reset during every new release of CodeSmith Generator. New versions of templates are added to the CodeSmith Generator template directory for the Major and Minor versions. However that is not the case for regular builds (identified via the assembly build number) for example: 5.3.x. Please note that this will also work if you want to reset your templates for the fun of it.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Delete dangling files from a Telligent Community database</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-delete-dangling-files-from-a-telligent-community-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 13:13:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-delete-dangling-files-from-a-telligent-community-database/</guid><description>The other day I came across a bug when upgrading my site to Community Server The Community Server 2008 upgrade tool would throw an exception when trying to move my files into CFS. The exception was result of the upgrade tool trying to pull down post attachments where the Section or Post didn&amp;rsquo;t exist.
This might not seem like such a bad thing, but it is for two reasons:
You have a file that is taking up database space that isn&amp;rsquo;t accessible within Community Server.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Reset a CodeSmith Generator license.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-reset-a-codesmith-generator-license/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 09:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-reset-a-codesmith-generator-license/</guid><description>Every once in a while you might run into a licensing problem when using CodeSmith Generator. This can be when the Visual Studio add-in becomes corrupted, or you encounter some kind of licensing problem and you have problems activating. You can fix these related problems by resetting the license file and reactivating your copy of CodeSmith Generator.
First you will need to exit all CodeSmith Generator related applications (CodeSmith Generator Studio, Visual Studio) and follow the steps below.</description></item><item><title>Video: Microsoft's 2008 Lang.NET Symposium</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-microsofts-2008-lang-net-symposium/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 22:32:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-microsofts-2008-lang-net-symposium/</guid><description>Check out the screen casts / videos of the Microsoft 2008 Lang.NET Symposium event. They have some pretty interesting videos available for everyone, granted you have Silverlight installed.
View 2008 Lang.NET Symposium Videos</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Silverlight 2.0 is almost here!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-silverlight-2.0-is-almost-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 14:18:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-silverlight-2.0-is-almost-here/</guid><description>Over the past week there has been some talk on Scott Guthrie and Shawn Burke blog about Silverlight 2.0. Please check out Scott&amp;rsquo;s blog for included features and eight walk through pertaining to Silverlight 2.0, and Shawn&amp;rsquo;s for more information on what we can expect while developing Silverlight 2.0 enabled applications.
Continue reading Scott Guthrie&amp;rsquo;s blog: First Look at Silverlight 2
Continue reading Shawn Burke&amp;rsquo;s blog: Getting to know Silverlight 2.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008 February CTP</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-february-ctp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 13:55:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-february-ctp/</guid><description>The February CTP of SQL Server 2008 has been released on Microsoft Download Center. From what I understand this CTP of SQL Server 2008 is feature complete. Please also check out the following article Breaking API changes in the February &amp;lsquo;08 CTP.
The download link to the CTP can be found below.
Overview Microsoft SQL Server 2008, the next release of Microsoft SQL Server, provides a comprehensive data platform that is more secure, reliable, manageable and scalable for your mission critical applications, while enabling developers to create new applications that can store and consume any type of data on any device, and enabling all your users to make informed decisions with relevant insights.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft's DreamSpark Program for Students</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsofts-dreamspark-program-for-students/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 17:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsofts-dreamspark-program-for-students/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Welcome to Microsoft DreamSpark Professional Developer and Designer tools for students at no charge.&amp;rdquo; (Microsoft)
I think this is really a great thing that Microsoft did for the students of the present and future. It allows students to get enriched in a great platform and at the same time use the leading tools of today to create their dreams. I am hoping that they open this program up to more students.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft XSLT Profiler Addin for Visual Studio 2008</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-xslt-profiler-addin-for-visual-studio-2008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-xslt-profiler-addin-for-visual-studio-2008/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;XML Tools team has released the XSLT Profiler Addin for VS 2008 - a quick and reliable performance analysis profiler tool that assists in the development and debugging of XSLT documents. The XSLT Profiler Addin for VS 2008 allows developers to measure, evaluate, and target performance-related problems in XSLT code by creating detailed XSLT performance reports. The XSLT Profiler includes a wealth of useful hints for XSL and XSLT style sheet optimizations, which are essential for XSLT-based applications that demand maximum performance.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio Themes</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 17:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-themes/</guid><description>Scott Hanselman has created a nice Visual Studio Programmer Themes Gallery that allows you to quickly pick a color scheme for your Visual Studio 2005/2008 IDE. I personally like a black theme, what about you?</description></item><item><title>How-to: Use Microsoft Windows Server 2008 as a workstation</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-windows-server-2008-as-a-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 17:03:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsoft-windows-server-2008-as-a-workstation/</guid><description>Windows Server 2008 is the fastest OS I have ever used. It&amp;rsquo;s truly amazing at how fast it performs every task I throw at it. With this said, below is a guide on how you can customize it to look just like vista. Making it a great looking development machine!!!
Enable Hardware Virtualization
My workstation is a x64 machine with hardware virtualization capabilities. This means I can run Hyper-V on my machine.</description></item><item><title>Top Three Reasons I cannot wait for Microsoft SQL Server 2008.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/top-three-reasons-i-cannot-wait-for-microsoft-sql-server-2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/top-three-reasons-i-cannot-wait-for-microsoft-sql-server-2008/</guid><description>There are many new features that are being shipped with Microsoft SQL Server 2008. But there were only a couple on that list that really stood out as a reason for me to upgrade to SQL Server 2008. What features are you most excited about in the Microsoft SQL Server 2008 release?
Data Compression: Enable data to be stored more effectively and reduce the storage requirements for your data. Data Compression also provides significant performance improvements for large I/O bound workloads like data warehousing.</description></item><item><title>Windows SideShow Device SDK for .Net Micro Framework 1.4</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/windows-sideshow-device-sdk-for-.net-micro-framework-1.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 23:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/windows-sideshow-device-sdk-for-.net-micro-framework-1.4/</guid><description>Overview Windows SideShow is a feature of Windows Vista that enables users to access information from their PCs on auxiliary displays. The Microsoft .NET Micro Framework 2.0 SP1 is the efficient runtime that powers today&amp;rsquo;s most popular SideShow-compatible devices. The Windows SideShow Device SDK enables developers to build SideShow-compatible devices using the .NET Micro Framework 2.0 SP1.
It includes sample code; portrait and landscape SideShow UI for QVGA displays (320x240); USB and Bluetooth connectivity; and the SideShow device simulator, which allows developers to test their firmware without physical hardware.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Device Emulator 3.0 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-device-emulator-3.0-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 11:17:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-device-emulator-3.0-released/</guid><description>Overview Microsoft Device Emulator 3.0 is the third publicly released version of the Device Emulator for ARM-based devices. This emulator will also release with Visual Studio 2008. Device Emulator 3.0 will replace the executables and DLLs from previous releases (1.0 and 2.0). The main addition with Device Emulator 3.0 is the new automation API for the device emulator manager, which allows developers programmatic access to perform the same operations on installed emulator images that can be performed interactively on the Device Emulator Manager drop-down and context menus.</description></item><item><title>You are Beautiful</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/you-are-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 13:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/you-are-beautiful/</guid><description>I just sat down and ate lunch and my mom was watching Extreme Makeover. I kept on seeing a pattern with what each wife&amp;rsquo;s husband told them when they were reunited. It was along the lines of &amp;ldquo;You are now beautiful&amp;rdquo;.
When I was growing up I always got the impression that an individual &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; base their relationships not on looks but for whom they are compatible with. We all are pretty unique individuals, but a majority of men have one thing in common: looks come first and personality follows.</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2008 is way faster than a Leopard..</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/windows-server-2008-is-way-faster-than-a-leopard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 12:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/windows-server-2008-is-way-faster-than-a-leopard/</guid><description>Last night my Windows Vista x64 Development box crashed and burned. This all came about after I rebooted my machine after a good days use and was greeted with a BSOD. After googling the words wudfrd which appeared in the BSOD, I found out that the ITunes update I installed earlier in the day was the root of the problem. Thanks Apple for taking the time to modify my system files for me.</description></item><item><title>.NET Framework Library Source Code now available</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/net-framework-library-source-code-now-available/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 06:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/net-framework-library-source-code-now-available/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this day for a very long time. Starting today you can view or debug the source code to the following .NET Framework libraries:
.NET Base Class Libraries (including System, System.CodeDom, System.Collections, System.ComponentModel, System.Diagnostics, System.Drawing, System.Globalization, System.IO, System.Net, System.Reflection, System.Runtime, System.Security, System.Text, System.Threading, etc). ASP.NET (System.Web, System.Web.Extensions) Windows Forms (System.Windows.Forms) Windows Presentation Foundation (System.Windows) ADO.NET and XML (System.Data and System.Xml) Shawn burke has a great blog post on how to configure your Visual Studio 2008 install to allow you to view the source code.</description></item><item><title>ReSharper 3.1 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/resharper-3.1-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 12:49:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/resharper-3.1-released/</guid><description>Jet Brains has finally released ReSharper 3.1. This is the first and much needed update to ReSharper since Visual Studio 2008 was released to manufactures. ReSharper 3.1 also contains new functionality like Solution Analysis (The ability to check an entire solution for errors/code improvements) and many bug fixes.
Download ReSharper 3.1</description></item><item><title>Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0 AJAX Templates for Visual Studio 2008</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-asp.net-2.0-ajax-templates-for-visual-studio-2008/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 15:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-asp.net-2.0-ajax-templates-for-visual-studio-2008/</guid><description>This release contains project templates for using Visual Studio 2008 or Visual Web Developer 2008 to create new web sites and web applications with ASP.NET 2.0 AJAX Extensions 1.0 features. The project templates contain specific references to assemblies in .NET Framework 2.0 and ASP.NET 2.0 AJAX Extensions 1.0 (Microsoft).
Download Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0 AJAX Templates for Visual Studio 2008</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008 Virtual Labs</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-virtual-labs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 11:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-virtual-labs/</guid><description>Two more of the hands-on labs from the Visual Studio 2008 Training Kit have been published as MSDN virtual labs. This allows you to can get started with VS 2008 in a minute and start exploring the new features. The two new labs focus on the language enhancements with C# 3.0 and Visual Basic 9. Here is a summary of the MSDN virtual labs that are now available:
What&amp;rsquo;s new in C# 3.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft PDC 2008 announced!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-pdc-2008-announced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 11:48:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-pdc-2008-announced/</guid><description>October 27-30, 2008
Pre-conference October 26, 2008
Los Angeles, California
We are delighted to announce the date and location of the next Microsoft Professional Developers Conference (PDC): October 27&amp;ndash;30, 2008 at the Los Angeles Convention Center. PDC is the definitive Microsoft event for software developers and architects focused on the future of the Microsoft platform. Mark your calendars and save the date. More information coming soon. (PDC08)</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 related downloads</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-related-downloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 09:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-related-downloads/</guid><description>The last couple of days have been better than Christmas for a few of us. Microsoft has been releasing many updates to its developer tools and sdk to go with the recent release of Visual Studio 2008. Below I have listed the updates that have been released with download links. Enjoy!
Visual Studio 2008 Download Express Versions here Download Retail Versions (MSDN subscribers only) here Download Trial Versions here Visual Studio 2008 SDK This is the official software development kit that allows developers to integrate tools, editors, designers, languages, and other features inside Visual Studio 2008.</description></item><item><title>Service Pack 1 released for .NET 2.0 and 3.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/service-pack-1-released-for-net-2.0-and-3.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/service-pack-1-released-for-net-2.0-and-3.0/</guid><description>Yesterday Microsoft complimented the release of Visual Studio 2008 with Service Pack 1 for both .NET 2.0 and 3.0. Information and download links are provided below.
&amp;ldquo;Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0 Service Pack 1 provides cumulative roll-up updates for customer reported issues found after the release of Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0. In addition, this release provides security improvements, and prerequisite feature support for .NET Framework 3.0 Service Pack 1, and .</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008 Has RTMed</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-has-rtmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 10:05:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-has-rtmed/</guid><description>If you have an MSDN subscriber account, you can download go Visual Studio 2008 and .NET 3.5 right now.</description></item><item><title>C# 3.0 and VB.NET 9.0 language specifications documents released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/csharp-3.0-and-vb.net-9.0-language-specifications-documents-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 10:51:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/csharp-3.0-and-vb.net-9.0-language-specifications-documents-released/</guid><description>Microsoft has released updated documents detailing the language specifications for C# 3.0 and VB.NET 9.0 (C# 3.0 and VB.NET 9.0 language specifications). These documents should take you quite some time to Enjoy!
Download C# 3.0 Language specifications VB.NET 9.0 Language specifications</description></item><item><title>Microsoft releases XSSDetect: A Cross Site Scripting detection plug-in for
Visual Studio</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-xssdetect-a-cross-site-scripting-detection-plug-in-for-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 10:18:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-xssdetect-a-cross-site-scripting-detection-plug-in-for-visual-studio/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;Ace&amp;rdquo; team inside of Microsoft has kindly released a plug-in for Visual Studio called XSSDetect. XSSDetect is a &amp;ldquo;static code analysis plug-in that will identify Cross-Site Scripting security flaws in any managed Web Application&amp;rdquo; (Microsoft).
XSSDetect analyzes .NET Intermediate Language (IL) read directly from the compiled binaries. It takes apart all assemblies, modules, classes and methods down to each instruction. It then identifies statements where untrusted user data enters the application and where dangerous methods are called.</description></item><item><title>How to attach a MS SQL database (.mdf) file with a missing log file (.ldf)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-attach-a-ms-sql-database-mdf-file-with-a-missing-log-file-ldf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 23:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-attach-a-ms-sql-database-mdf-file-with-a-missing-log-file-ldf/</guid><description>Tonight I ran into a dilemma where I was only supplied with a Microsoft SQL .mdf file. I thought that I would have no problems and just have to attach the database file and Microsoft SQL would rebuild the log file for me.
I was wrong and it didn&amp;rsquo;t take any longer than five minutes for me to figure that out. I thought to myself that quite a few people would have had the same problem as me and a solution would be available the World Wide Web.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft offers four free GBs of Silverlight hosting!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-offers-four-free-gbs-of-silverlight-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 16:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-offers-four-free-gbs-of-silverlight-hosting/</guid><description>Microsoft is offering four GBs of hosting space to anyone needing a place to host there Silverlight applications. I just hope a lot of people will see the importance in the stance Microsoft is taking on this subject. So what are you waiting for? Go and get yourself some free hosting.
Microsoft® Silverlight™ Streaming by Windows Live™ is a companion service for Silverlight that makes it easier for developers and designers to deliver and scale rich media as part of their Silverlight applications.</description></item><item><title>Releasing the Source Code for the .NET Framework Libraries</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/releasing-the-source-code-for-the-.net-framework-libraries/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 13:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/releasing-the-source-code-for-the-.net-framework-libraries/</guid><description>I thought that I would never see the day, that Microsoft releases the source code to the .Net framework. I&amp;rsquo;m betting that the Mono Project is having a party as we speak!
One of the things my team has been working to enable has been the ability for .NET developers to download and browse the source code of the .NET Framework libraries, and to easily enable debugging support in them.</description></item><item><title>Video: Visual Studio 2008 Training</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-visual-studio-2008-training/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 10:47:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/video-visual-studio-2008-training/</guid><description>Do you want to learn about the new features of Visual Studio 2008, and various related technologies? I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even know where to start? Well look no further, because Microsoft recently published some videos to get everyone up to speed. The best part is all of the videos are free!
View Visual Studio 2008 Training Videos</description></item><item><title>Object Initializers in C# 3.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/object-initializers-in-csharp-3.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 16:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/object-initializers-in-csharp-3.0/</guid><description>The other day I was doing my usual reading and came across some really cool information on Dan Wahlin&amp;rsquo;s blog about what we can expect in C# 3.0. Even though I disagree with some of the specs of C# 3.0, there are some really cool features worth noting in C# 3.0 like object initializers.
&amp;ldquo;C# 3.0 is just around the corner so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d start writing about a few of the features that it exposes and provide quick and concise examples of how they can be used.</description></item><item><title>Security Update for Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/security-update-for-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 10:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/security-update-for-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</guid><description>Just a reminder to everyone to check windows updates often. Yesterday Microsoft released a critical patch for any Windows Machines that have Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack1 installed. To download this update visit the windows update website.
Read KB37061</description></item><item><title>Microsoft releases Silverlight 1.0 RTM</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-silverlight-1.0-rtm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 07:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-silverlight-1.0-rtm/</guid><description>Last night Microsoft released version 1.0 of Silverlight. Silverlight is a very new and exciting product that will change the way we see the web.
Compelling Cross-Platform User Experiences Deliver media experiences and rich interactive applications for the Web that incorporate video, animation, interactivity and stunning user interfaces.
Seamless, fast installation for users, thanks to a small, on-demand, easy-to-install plug-in that is under 2 megabytes (MB) in size and works with all leading browsers.</description></item><item><title>Back to school</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/back-to-school/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 08:41:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/back-to-school/</guid><description>The past week was kind of hectic, first of all I arrived back home to a damaged home. It took a while to clean up the mess even with determined family members and friends. In the near future I will be trying to get some pictures up on facebook of the mess. Now that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry too much about that, I can focus my attention on school, development, and relaxation.</description></item><item><title>DasBlog to Telligent Community Server 2.0 blog converter</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/dasblog-to-telligent-community-server-2.0-blog-converter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 17:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/dasblog-to-telligent-community-server-2.0-blog-converter/</guid><description>My friend Ryan Hoffman, who is currently interning at Telligent; has created a DasBlog to Community Server 2.1 blog converter. Hopefully like my Firefox to IE7 application will let others experience different applications in the same category of software; in this case blogging.
I highly recommend anyone with DasBlog to test this out and let me and Ryan know what you think.</description></item><item><title>My Last Day</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-last-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 15:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-last-day/</guid><description>Today was my last day at Telligent as many of you already know. During this internship I learned many things that one can never learn by watching the television or going to college. Here are a few things I learned from some certain individuals:
How to act in a corporate environment (I would like to see college teach that!) How to express my ideas in a more appealing way. Keep my desk nailed and chained to the floor.</description></item><item><title>Heading back home to a natural disaster</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/heading-back-home-to-a-natural-disaster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 14:43:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/heading-back-home-to-a-natural-disaster/</guid><description>Lately back home the flooding has been pretty terrible, in 3 days I will be flying back home to all this flooding. However Last night, I received two phone calls from my brother and dad, informing me that a tornado had taken out our shop and garage and had also hit the addition onto our house. I was pretty bummed about this whole situation until I found out that my 1967 Barracuda was flattened.</description></item><item><title>Hotfix available for Visual Studio 2005 F5 Debugging Performance Issue with ASP.NET</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hotfix-available-for-visual-studio-2005-f5-debugging-performance-issue-with-asp.net/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 17:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hotfix-available-for-visual-studio-2005-f5-debugging-performance-issue-with-asp.net/</guid><description>Scott Guthrie has released news of a new hotfix available for Visual Studio 2005. It resolves a infrequent performance issue when trying to debug an ASP.NET application.
Over the last year we&amp;rsquo;ve seen several people report having performance problems when using F5 to run/debug ASP.NET 2.0 applications using Visual Studio 2005. The problem in theses cases typically wasn&amp;rsquo;t with building the project, but rather that it sometimes took the debugger a really long time to hit the first breakpoint once it attached to the application (45+ seconds and longer sometimes).</description></item><item><title>One Week Left</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/one-week-left/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 13:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/one-week-left/</guid><description>This coming Saturday I&amp;rsquo;m leaving on a jet plane to head back to good ole&amp;rsquo; Wisconsin. I&amp;rsquo;m going to miss everything about Telligent, a lot. It became my extended family. I have truly learned a lot about Telligent like:
How to act in a corporate environment How many great employees there are How everyone is really intelligent Anyone can tap into another&amp;rsquo;s knowledge During this past week, my fellow interns, who I work with daily, have started to head back to class.</description></item><item><title>Graffiti</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/graffiti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 13:05:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/graffiti/</guid><description>During the past week we had a hack-a-thon event at Telligent headquarters. At the beginning of the week, I kept hearing small snippets of Graffiti. So I asked Jason Alexander what it was, and even though he was secretive about it. All he said is that it&amp;rsquo;s a CMS solution.
During our hack-a-thon, Graffiti was shown off to all the Telligenti who were in town, most of us had no clue that Graffiti even existed.</description></item><item><title>Settling For Second Place.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/settling-for-second-place/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 13:02:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/settling-for-second-place/</guid><description>During last week when all the remote Telligenti were in the office, we had the first ever Telligent hack-a-thon. The target of this coding event was to add any feature you thought Graffiti (A new CMS solution) should have. The hack-a-thon at first, was only going to be one prize, which went to the best hacked submission for Graffiti. However, after more than 15 great submissions, Telligent decided the top three submissions would get an 8gig IPhone.</description></item><item><title>The All nighter</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-all-nighter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 10:03:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-all-nighter/</guid><description>Yesterday, Telligent had a hack-a-thon; and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy that they let an intern participate. I ended up staying up all night and implementing a project with the amazing markup and designer extraordinaire Ken Hanson.
I feel like the project that Ken and I developed was pretty solid and cool, However there are many brilliant minds that work at Telligent and most of them had their own projects. Some projects were pretty spectacular, so only time will tell who will win an 8GB iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Are your flash objects stealing your screen?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/are-your-flash-objects-stealing-your-screen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 13:53:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/are-your-flash-objects-stealing-your-screen/</guid><description>The past week here, in Dallas, has been the busiest so far. I have been working on a new navigation bar for Community Server Enterprise Reporting. I also have been making phone calls and getting everything in place for when school starts.
In other news, Telligent is flying in all the remote employees. They should all be here by tonight, so tomorrow will be a really fun day; meeting all the Telligent employees.</description></item><item><title>The G35 experience</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-g35-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 14:42:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-g35-experience/</guid><description>Some of you might be thinking of a top secret Logitech product. I know I was when I heard the utterance &amp;ldquo;G35.&amp;rdquo; The G35 is a pretty sweet car and thanks to Donnie, in sales, I was lucky enough to get my first ride in one today. I have noticed that a lot of people here in Texas own a G35. Back home no one has one. In fact, I saw my first one when I arrived in Dallas.</description></item><item><title>The FileSystemWatcher class and medium trust.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-filesystemwatcher-class-and-medium-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 19:18:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-filesystemwatcher-class-and-medium-trust/</guid><description>This morning I sat down and started looking at why Community Server Enterprise Reporting was having problems running under medium trust. I kept on thinking something is majorly wrong if Community Server can run under medium trust and we can&amp;rsquo;t. I figured that all the reflection we use in Community Server Enterprise Reporting was causing the problems. Then I remembered that Community Server uses reflection. If Community Server uses reflection in a couple places then that&amp;rsquo;s not the reason Enterprise Reporting is blowing up.</description></item><item><title>Product Documentation</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/product-documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 13:40:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/product-documentation/</guid><description>This afternoon I started on creating the documentation for how to customize Community Server Enterprise Reporting. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be working on this for a while, because there are so many things one can customize, like:
Multiple database connections, Declarative report model, Enabling and disabling reports, Configuring reports, And much more! One thing that I have noticed over the past couple of years is that a lot of the documentation running in the wild is usually not that good.</description></item><item><title>Caching and What It Can Do For Your Product</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/caching-and-what-it-can-do-for-your-product/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 15:04:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/caching-and-what-it-can-do-for-your-product/</guid><description>Today I updated Community Server Enterprise Reporting caching framework to use Telligent&amp;rsquo;s updated caching framework. This updated caching framework is truly amazing; it can handle many more requests and data than the previous version.
After updating Community Server Enterprise Reporting, I started to see if the caching framework could handle more than what we were previously testing. Let me be the first to say that you can run every report we have and cache all of it with ease.</description></item><item><title>I am beginning to like the idea of shipping...</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/i-am-beginning-to-like-the-idea-of-shipping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 15:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/i-am-beginning-to-like-the-idea-of-shipping/</guid><description>I bet you all thought that I was going to talk about shipping Community Sever Enterprise Reporting. I would, but then I would be lying and I don&amp;rsquo;t lie. This morning I shipped a fifty pound package back home. I am so happy that Adam and I decided that we would ship clothes and extra stuff that we have acquired down here, back home. My return flight should now be about fifty pounds lighter!</description></item><item><title>Automated Unit Testing</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/automated-unit-testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 16:17:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/automated-unit-testing/</guid><description>Automated Unit testing is one subject that I do not know too much about. I was wishing this summer that we would get the chance to unit test the Community Server Enterprise Reporting project. We will see what the near future brings; I think we are not unit testing because the code is constantly changing. Once we get a little further down the road, I can see us running some unit tests on our project.</description></item><item><title>Repeater Control, Is it really that Dynamic?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/repeater-control-is-it-really-that-dynamic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 10:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/repeater-control-is-it-really-that-dynamic/</guid><description>My question to everyone, Is the Repeater control dynamic enough to create custom tables on the fly? When I think of dynamic it&amp;rsquo;s something you have complete control over. And can change the display at anytime during execution. Please note that I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are multiple ways one can accomplish what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, this is the way I choose to do it.
The one thing about the repeater control is it&amp;rsquo;s great for making data that has a unique predefined header and footer.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008: Smarter Intellisense</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-smarter-intellisense/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2007 19:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-smarter-intellisense/</guid><description>Scott Guthrie showed off some new features that he&amp;rsquo;s recently learned. This feature is new to Visual Studio and has been one that I have been waiting for since Visual Studio .NET 2003. Have you ever been typing and needed to look at something behind Intellisense?
It happens to me quite a bit since I started using Visual Studio .NET 2003.
Now while Intellisense is being displayed, one can hit the control key and the Intellisense becomes transparent.</description></item><item><title>New Features in Visual Studio 2008 Beta 2</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/new-features-in-visual-studio-2008-beta-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 19:40:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/new-features-in-visual-studio-2008-beta-2/</guid><description>Microsoft recently released its next beta version of Visual Studio 2008. Microsoft has targeted all types of users with the Visual Studio 2008 release by including an updated MSDN Library, Express, Standard, Professional and Enterprise versions of Beta 2.
&amp;ldquo;With this beta release, Visual Studio 2008 is 99 percent complete, according to a Microsoft spokeswoman&amp;rdquo; (PC WORLD).
Below is more information about the release of Visual Studio 2008 Beta 2 and where you can download it.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/cryptography/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/cryptography/</guid><description>I had so much fun last night, Jason Alexander is so awesome. He took us to Dave and Busters last night! I think I had the most fun out of everyone there (Interns, Jason, Rob, and Snelson Stopped by for a minute). I&amp;rsquo;ve really never been to a place that big before, the only place that I&amp;rsquo;ve been to that was even remotely in the same category was chucky cheese in like 4th grade.</description></item><item><title>The Rules of Subversion (SVN)!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-rules-of-subversion-svn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 16:27:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-rules-of-subversion-svn/</guid><description>I had quite the experience today, for one I committed the Community Server Enterprise Reporting (CSER) Installer into the Repository of Community Server&amp;rsquo;s Installer. EEK! So I quickly did a &amp;ldquo;revert&amp;rdquo; on the folder to what it previously was before I had changed anything.
So here is the story on how it all happened. A few days ago I grabbed down the newest Community Server revision off of svn and copied the installer folder from CS into our project and started rewriting the installer for our project.</description></item><item><title>Community Server Enterprise Reporting Release Date</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/community-server-enterprise-reporting-release-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 23:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/community-server-enterprise-reporting-release-date/</guid><description>Telligent let the word out and posted a release date on the forums. Around September 1st, we will be releasing beta one of Community Server Enterprise Reporting. For the past two days I have been working on the installer for Community Server Enterprise Reporting. Hopefully tomorrow morning I&amp;rsquo;ll finish the small little bit of work that still needs to be done. That is if nothing else jumps out at me!</description></item><item><title>Oh Snap!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/oh-snap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 14:44:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/oh-snap/</guid><description>Today I heard a few words being yelled out into the hallway from a fellow intern. When this happens, I always take the time off and investigate because I know something has gone wrong. In this case, Andrew broke the build again today.
The build breaker wasn&amp;rsquo;t a programming bug, he just forgot to close Visual Studio, so it never saved the project file. This caused the build to break because the project file contains what&amp;rsquo;s included in the project.</description></item><item><title>A glimpse of Community Server Enterprise Reporting!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-glimpse-of-community-server-enterprise-reporting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 10:02:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-glimpse-of-community-server-enterprise-reporting/</guid><description>I believe that the other interns and I have done a really great job this week! We have sat down and got a ton of work done in a short amount of time. After the meeting on Friday with Jason Alexander and Rob Howard, I could see it that we are where we need to be. Rob Howard even announced on his blog that he was going to show off some screenshots this weekend!</description></item><item><title>What would we do without Air Conditioning?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-would-we-do-without-air-conditioning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 22:37:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-would-we-do-without-air-conditioning/</guid><description>As one might suspect the weather here in Dallas is starting to return to normal. We have had three days of fairly nice weather with only a little bit of rain falling today. I can feel that August is going to bring some warm weather. I really don&amp;rsquo;t mind warm weather that much, because I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be in where it&amp;rsquo;s nice and cool.
When you tell someone that your living down in Texas they are always like &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be so 110 outside everyday&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Tellicamp: Bring your sleeping bag and toothbrush!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/tellicamp-bring-your-sleeping-bag-and-toothbrush/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 17:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/tellicamp-bring-your-sleeping-bag-and-toothbrush/</guid><description>The weather during the past two days has been absolutely spectacular! I wish we were a little closer to the gulf so I could take a quick ride to the beach.
I really like the new task website (Tellicamp); I know exactly what myself and co-workers have to get done by the end of the day! The Telliterns have quickly killed the list of TODOs. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait till see tomorrows feedback from Rob Howard, Jason Alexander and the rest of the Telligent.</description></item><item><title>Want to learn Microsoft .Net? Look no further!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/want-to-learn-microsoft-net-look-no-further/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 20:31:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/want-to-learn-microsoft-net-look-no-further/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the mood to learn something new then you have came to the right place. I have been meaning to write this post for quite some time! Lately I have come across a few people who asked me &amp;ldquo;How can I learn about C# and ASP.NET?&amp;rdquo; I have told them all the same response, my response is to check out a few free websites that contain some great lessons that Microsoft has provided the community.</description></item><item><title>What a beautiful day!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-a-beautiful-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 15:50:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-a-beautiful-day/</guid><description>Today was one of those rare days when you wake up and it actually doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like it is going to rain. Well maybe not so rare here normally, but it sure has been so far this summer.
All the guys besides Andrew continued working on the UI and its starting to really take shape. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait till Friday and look back on what Community Server Enterprise Reporting looked like yesterday.</description></item><item><title>Looking at multiviews of reporting</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/looking-at-multiviews-of-reporting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 09:14:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/looking-at-multiviews-of-reporting/</guid><description>Yesterday was a pretty interesting day if you ask me. For one we set up a new system to keep track of tasks, bugs and feedback, which is pretty sweet. Not only will this help us manage what needs to be done, it will change the way our scrum meetings are held.
I worked on the User Interface for adding a report with Howdy; it uses MultiViews and reminds me of a wizard!</description></item><item><title>The top five reasons why I'm going to love Visual Studio 2008</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-top-five-reasons-why-im-going-to-love-visual-studio-2008/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 19:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-top-five-reasons-why-im-going-to-love-visual-studio-2008/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve have been waiting along time for Visual Studio 2008, because it adds functionality that should have been included a long time ago. I have pondered a while on what makes Visual Studio 2008 so special and what it would take me to upgrade. I came up with five good reasons I think I should upgrade to Visual Studio 2008.
1. Nested Master Pages After working with the Community Server SDK, I&amp;rsquo;ve found out that Visual Studio 2005 comes up short.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008 launch and availability dates</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-launch-and-availability-dates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2008-launch-and-availability-dates/</guid><description>I am sure by now a lot of you have heard that Visual Studio 2008, Windows
Server 2008, and SQL Server 2008 will** launch** on February 27th, 2008. However, what a lot of people do not realize is that a product will be released to manufacturers (RTM) long before it is actually &amp;ldquo;launched&amp;rdquo;. So anyone with access to an MSDN account will be able to download Visual Studio 2008 and possibly Windows Server 2008 and SQL Server 2008 before this year ends.</description></item><item><title>My first ever IHOP...</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-first-ever-ihop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-first-ever-ihop/</guid><description>We got notice late last night that Jason Alexander was not feeling so well and let us know that Bill Robertson would be taking charge for the day.
I worked on fixing some bugs earlier this morning and that was quite the learning experience. This afternoon Andrew and I continued working on the task engine, and then I attempted to run the task engine in a configuration that we have never done before, remote source db to remote destination db.</description></item><item><title>Flooding the North Dallas .NET User Group</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/flooding-the-north-dallas-net-user-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 22:13:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/flooding-the-north-dallas-net-user-group/</guid><description>Last night I attended the North Dallas .NET User Group (NDDNUG) after Shane Henderson maneuvered his truck like a boat down the road because the streets were practically flooded. This was the first user group of any kind that I have attended. Luckily the topic was on something I knew a lot about, Windows Vista. I&amp;rsquo;m a Windows guy. I always have to be running on the newest possible thing. Even if that means that I have to run an alpha version of Windows.</description></item><item><title>Movie and game night</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/movie-and-game-night/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 15:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/movie-and-game-night/</guid><description>Howdy and I worked today on implementing a declarative report model into Community Server Enterprise Reporting. One can now choose to define a report in xml or add the class assembly information into the report configuration section.
I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to game night. A bunch of the guys are going to be playing WOW and some people are going to play Counter-Strike: Source. I don&amp;rsquo;t play video games very much anymore so we will see the outcome.</description></item><item><title>Game Night Tomorrow Night!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/game-night-tomorrow-night/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 17:27:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/game-night-tomorrow-night/</guid><description>Today was another case of the Mondays! Just kidding! This morning we had our scrum meeting and found ourselves with a lot of tasks that still needed to be checked in.
Today for lunch, Telligent catered in &amp;ldquo;Red Hot &amp;amp; Blue&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Who names their company &amp;ldquo;Red Hot &amp;amp; Blue&amp;rdquo;? I think they could have come up with a better name, but anyways we were lucky enough to taste their BBQ Brisket and BBQ Smoked Turkey.</description></item><item><title>The one and only Community Server Enterprise Reporting Presentation</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-one-and-only-community-server-enterprise-reporting-presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2007 16:16:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-one-and-only-community-server-enterprise-reporting-presentation/</guid><description>Today we all shoved into the C# conference room after we all devoured some Olive Garden. It was really good. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had breadsticks or visited Olive Garden in quite some time. Our presentation lasted about an hour; overall I think it went pretty well.
David Penton and Bill Robertson found some things that we are going to change in Community Server Enterprise Reporting. The Telligent listeners raised some valid scenarios that we will have to take into consideration for version one and two.</description></item><item><title>C-Rollin through PowerPoint's</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/c-rollin-through-powerpoints/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2007 15:23:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/c-rollin-through-powerpoints/</guid><description>Today was a big change; The Tellitern crew sat in the VB .Net conference room and created a PowerPoint. Tomorrow, if you&amp;rsquo;re in the office, come and support the three month &amp;ldquo;FTE&amp;rdquo; (cough Darren cough) Interns. We will be presenting Community Server Enterprise Reporting (Tattletale) to interested Telligent employees.
Jason Alexander and the interns went to C-Rolls Sushi for lunch. I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to really like Sushi; the lady working at C-Rolls made my day by providing me a plastic cheater clip for my chop sticks.</description></item><item><title>Happy 4th</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/happy-4th/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 14:56:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/happy-4th/</guid><description>Tomorrow most of the people at Telligent will be taking the day off, however there are a lot of hard working people at Telligent that are still coming in. We were offered to take off a little bit earlier today if we wanted. This was pretty cool of Telligent. I was unable to take off early due to a couple of the guys came up to me and asked me if I wanted to play some counter-strike: source.</description></item><item><title>It's a case of the Mondays</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/its-a-case-of-the-mondays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 20:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/its-a-case-of-the-mondays/</guid><description>Over the weekend Ryan and I made some major changes to how we implement reports. It took a little bit of time to fix those 689 errors that had to be changed in order for us to be able to compile.
Today we had a small meeting with the other interns and discussed the changes that we made to the reporting base classes. And then we went I went onto correcting a list of things that needed to be done.</description></item><item><title>Rafain is awesome</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/rafain-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 16:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/rafain-is-awesome/</guid><description>Today was not the ordinary Friday that I usually look forward to. To start out the day Jason Alexander asked us where we wanted to eat. The interns took a quick vote and decided to go to Rafain. I really love Rafain because it is so delicious. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know what Rafain is? It is a Brazilian steakhouse that ROCKS! The interns as a whole ate way too much including Jason (who was on a diet).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Rain Forest we call Texas</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/welcome-to-the-rain-forest-we-call-texas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 22:48:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/welcome-to-the-rain-forest-we-call-texas/</guid><description>As we were watching the news today, we found out that we are about to surpass all previous rainfall records for Texas. That is pretty amazing considering its summer time and Texas is usually a desert during the end of June.
Howdy and I cranked out the rest of the reports that we were working on. I also added some more functionality to our framework. I am looking forward to the weekend so I can laugh at all the people who bought the IPhone, and watch the new Die Hard.</description></item><item><title>ReSharper 3.0 plug-ins</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/resharper-3.0-plug-ins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 22:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/resharper-3.0-plug-ins/</guid><description>Please note that I will continually update this list as I discover newsworthy ReSharper plug One free plug-in for ReSharper 3.0 that I recently found is DT.ReSharperPlugin. DT.ReSharperPlugin makes it extremely easy for anyone to quickly implement localization into new or existing applications. Below is a couple cool features that DT.ReSharperPlugin adds to Visual Studio 2005.
Move strings to resource Move strings to resource by context action. Replace string by property If string exists in project resource files, then use &amp;ldquo;Replace string by property&amp;rdquo; context action.</description></item><item><title>STORM! We do not own an amphibious car.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/storm-we-do-not-own-an-amphibious-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 23:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/storm-we-do-not-own-an-amphibious-car/</guid><description>I had my first bagel today; I don�t ever recall having one before, so if I did it was way long ago. I thought they the beagles that I ate were pretty delicious.
Howdy and I are getting pretty good at writing some fairly complex SQL queries. I think that by the time this internship is over. I can pretty much sit down and write any query that I could think of off the top of my head.</description></item><item><title>Stormy weather returns.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/stormy-weather-returns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/stormy-weather-returns/</guid><description>Dallas normally doesn&amp;rsquo;t get to much rain during the summer, so it must be something out of the ordinary for the locals. I kind of like it because the rain brings down the overall temperature.
Everyone continued working on SQL queries for the reports today. I am noticing that I have no problem writing SQL statements. Howdy and I are learning tips and tricks as we progress through the queries. I really wish that colleges would teach SQL to students in the Computer Science major.</description></item><item><title>Paintball: where techies of all ages become kids.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/paintball-where-techies-of-all-ages-become-kids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 20:13:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/paintball-where-techies-of-all-ages-become-kids/</guid><description>On Friday, Telligent gave everyone the day off to play paintball. I had a lot of fun playing, and enjoyed seeing people older than me running, and diving into a new &amp;ldquo;safe area.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a lot of Telligenti including myself were sore for the remainder of the weekend. The soreness was definitely worth it; thanks Telligent!
After riding into work today with Rick Reszler, we noticed that Adam had a new office.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Visual Studio 2005 Add-Ins</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-favorite-visual-studio-2005-add-ins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 20:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-favorite-visual-studio-2005-add-ins/</guid><description>I have been using Windows Vista on my laptop for two solid years. I thought it was about time to dual boot my machine with Windows XP Professional. I find that my battery life and performance has greatly increased compared to Vista. I use my laptop for development, so the first thing I did after dual booting is installed Visual Studio 2005 Team Suite with SP1.
I think a lot of developers in general are not using the full potential that Visual Studio has to offer.</description></item><item><title>Anyone wanna play a round of musical offices?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/anyone-wanna-play-a-round-of-musical-offices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 15:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/anyone-wanna-play-a-round-of-musical-offices/</guid><description>Today was a lot of fun, have you ever heard about musical chairs? How about musical offices? That&amp;rsquo;s right! I was lucky enough to play musical offices today! W00T! I believe Telligent owns the patent on this game.
During all of this, Andrew and I wrote the code for a custom control in the Ping Pong and game room number 2. I&amp;rsquo;m really glad that I own a laptop.
Tomorrow most of Telligent is taking the day off to play paint ball.</description></item><item><title>Mole!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/mole/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2007 23:15:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/mole/</guid><description>The task engine has been completed, and I sure do notice when a bulk insert is running because we currently have my machine running as the main SQL Server. This week were focusing on the UI, Charting and such things like that.
There was so much drama at Telligent today. One might have thought that Telligent was actually the CIA, seeking out a mole in the organization. One might ask who that mole was, it was Adam, and he even had me his roommate fooled.</description></item><item><title>Cloudy</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/cloudy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 17:03:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/cloudy/</guid><description>We all knew that we would need to rewrite the task framework; it was somewhat messy and needed an overhaul. Ryan Hoffman and I overhauled it last night in a few hours. So this morning we quickly fixed most of the queries to use the new engine. Let me be the first to say, these tasks are quick!
However there are some tasks need to update data that was imported previously (counters and other such data).</description></item><item><title>Our first review day!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/our-first-review-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 08:21:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/our-first-review-day/</guid><description>Today at our scrum meeting Jason Alexander told us that we would be reviewing Tattletale to Scott Watermasysk and Rob Howard after lunch. So we spent a part of the day cleaning up the code (which was needed a little bit). Soon we realized when we were testing our reports during the cleanup, that someone updated our db schema and deleted some tables, and that we would need to rerun the tasks.</description></item><item><title>Houston: We have t-minus two months!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/houston-we-have-t-minus-two-months/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 18:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/houston-we-have-t-minus-two-months/</guid><description>I really cannot believe that a month has passed since I arrived in Texas. The internship is 33% completed and it seems like three percent.
Today we cranked out reports and we only have two left. Everyone thought that it was going to take three days to write one report. However, Andrew and I have written twenty plus reports in one week! The same goes for the rest of the gang.</description></item><item><title>SELECT PostTitle AS 'This Is An Okay Title' FROM Tattletale_ForumData WHERE PostTitle IS NOT NULL</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/select-posttitle-as-this-is-an-okay-title-from-tattletale-forumdata-where-posttitle-is-not-null/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 17:21:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/select-posttitle-as-this-is-an-okay-title-from-tattletale-forumdata-where-posttitle-is-not-null/</guid><description>Today was another dreadful day of having problems with the task framework. We wrote four blog reports today, which is not nearly the amount that we have written in the past, but overall today I think I got a lot accomplished.
We all meet around 11:00 am this morning for our SCRUM meeting; a little late due to Ado had other meetings to attend to. We recognized that we had a few priority ten tasks that needed to be completed today.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008 June CTP Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-june-ctp-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 11:52:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-june-ctp-released/</guid><description>Today Microsoft released the first CTP of SQL Server 2008. Be sure to download and try it out.
Microsoft SQL Server 2008, the next release of Microsoft SQL Server, provides a comprehensive data platform that is more secure, reliable, manageable and scalable for your mission critical applications, while enabling developers to create new applications that can store and consume any type of data on any device, and enabling all your users to make informed decisions with relevant insights.</description></item><item><title>The day the JOIN(s) died.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-day-the-joins-died/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 08:31:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-day-the-joins-died/</guid><description>After arriving to work with we started estimating how long our reports would take to complete. Little did we all know that we would run into problems soon enough. Telligent supplied us with a delicious and much appreciated breakfast this morning. After Ryan, Adam and I came back from lunch; we opened our car door and then heard a massive sound coming from Mother Nature. Right after this happened Adam said maybe we should go back and unplug some things.</description></item><item><title>Reports and Game night!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/reports-and-game-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 11:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/reports-and-game-night/</guid><description>Today, we got into the office and worked on reports all day, we found a few flaws in our framework and made the necessary changes. This week we all have been estimating and recalculating how long it will take us to get the reports done. I like that we are doing this, so in future references when a client asks us how long something will take. We can estimate to the best of our abilities how long something should take and bill them accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Warm weather rocks!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/warm-weather-rocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 16:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/warm-weather-rocks/</guid><description>I am happy to be back in Texas because it removed some of the distressing memories that were occurring at home. I woke up at 1:30 am on Sunday morning in order to get ready for my return to Dallas. The three hour drive was a little much considering my plane took off at 6:00 am. After flying through another turbulent flight, we touched down in around 8:20 am. From there Ryan came and picked me up and we went back to the apartment.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft ASP.NET AJAX Control Toolkit Update Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-asp.net-ajax-control-toolkit-update-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2007 21:03:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-asp.net-ajax-control-toolkit-update-released/</guid><description>I love seeing updates to the ASP.NET AJAX Control Toolkit; I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the lookout for updates to ASP.NET AJAX. There are various AJAX add in solutions, but I think this one is by far the most popular.
Yesterday the ASP.NET AJAX Control Toolkit team ajax.asp.net web-site.
The ASP.NET AJAX Control Toolkit is a free download and contains more than 40 additional AJAX controls and components that work on top of the core ASP.</description></item><item><title>Looking for a Mission Critical Operating System?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/looking-for-a-mission-critical-operating-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2007 20:19:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/looking-for-a-mission-critical-operating-system/</guid><description>During my daily reading this afternoon, the following post on blogs.msdn.com caught my eye. Apparently NASA uses XP on some of its mission critical machines. Someone at Microsoft managed to snap the following picture from a TV screen at the Houston Mission Control Center
Source Backstage @ Robotics I find it ironic that NASA has had security problems in the past. Yet they still have not upgraded to the &amp;ldquo;most secure system to date&amp;rdquo; Windows Vista.</description></item><item><title>Back in Wisconsin.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/back-in-wisconsin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 10:46:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/back-in-wisconsin/</guid><description>Yesterday I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to write a blog post, so here it is :). I focused on hooking up the web services so we could get onto the next task of writing reports. Telligent supplied its employee&amp;rsquo;s with pigs in a blanket for breakfast. It was really good. I had a lot of fun yesterday at work, it just seemed like everything was fitting into place.
I flew out around 5:30 after our airplane had to deal with customs for EVER before flying us to our destination.</description></item><item><title>The Perfect Day!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-perfect-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2007 17:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-perfect-day/</guid><description>Today was such a beautiful day! We walked outside our apartment this morning and the weather was so perfect it felt surreal. This morning we got introduced to our stand in project manager ado who will be filling in next week. I also exchanged my phone that split in two for a PPC-6700.
For lunch Delia and Laura took Adam, Ryan, and I out to Potbelly&amp;rsquo;s for some delicious food. And we all talked about our roller coaster experiences.</description></item><item><title>Headache +2, Me = 0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/headache-2-me-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 18:43:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/headache-2-me-0/</guid><description>I swear that this weekend just flew by; it is almost like I shut my eyes on Friday night and woke up this morning. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything this weekend, but watch a movie and relax after receiving some bad news. On Wednesday I&amp;rsquo;m flying back to Wisconsin for a few days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to put up some pictures.
Today, I worked on web services and even more on the User Interface.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008 and Visual Studio 2008 announced!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-and-visual-studio-2008-announced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 13:50:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2008-and-visual-studio-2008-announced/</guid><description>I so can&amp;rsquo;t wait for these two products to ship!
Microsoft** revealed the official names Monday of the next major upgrades to its Visual Studio software development tools platform and its SQL Server database, which will be called, simply, Visual Studio 2008 and SQL Server 2008.
The company announced these names during the Microsoft TechEd 2007 conference in Orlando, Fla., which began on Monday. The Visual Studio upgrade had been codenamed &amp;ldquo;Orcas,&amp;rdquo; while SQL Server has had the &amp;ldquo;Katmai&amp;rdquo; code name.</description></item><item><title>Telligent turns Three!!!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/telligent-turns-three/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 17:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/telligent-turns-three/</guid><description>Today Telligent celebrated its third birthday by calling everyone into the ping pong room. Once we were all in there; it was revealed to us that there was a card board clone of Rob Howard. As soon as Rob Howard walked in the room he started laughing and the first words out of his mouth were &amp;ldquo;It was Tom wasn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;
Today, I continued working on the User Interface. However, I mostly focused on working with chained events/delegates and User Controls.</description></item><item><title>Community Server 2007 migration bug</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/community-server-2007-migration-bug/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 23:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/community-server-2007-migration-bug/</guid><description>Tonight we updated windowscoding.com to Community Server 2007. After a while of messing around I noticed that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t access and blog posts. Soon enough, after enough looking around we noticed that the query string had \themes\blogs obviously something was wrong. So I went and messaged my friend and twice time co-worker Rick Reszler if he had any clue as to the reason of my error. He quickly told me that this happens on some sites only after they are migrated from 2.</description></item><item><title>No rain... what a change!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/no-rain-what-a-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 17:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/no-rain-what-a-change/</guid><description>Today in Dallas, Texas we actually had a nice day. Although, it was cloudy when I checked but that is better than rain right?
My fellow interns came into my office a few times today and told me that I am a hard worker. Thanks! All that I can say is that I love the work we are doing and I am very committed to it. Last night, I ended up working on the User Interface until the master page was done.</description></item><item><title>The Community Server Enterprise Reporting User Interface!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-community-server-enterprise-reporting-user-interface/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 15:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/the-community-server-enterprise-reporting-user-interface/</guid><description>This morning we woke up and headed out the door like usual; however, a bird keeps on attacking Adam, so now every time we leave our apartment he sprints to the car. When we arrived at work it was nice and bright outside. But by the time we had devoured the breakfast that Telligent had bought for its employees and in our SCRUM meeting, it was pitch black!
It has been raining so much; a person visiting from Seattle might forget where he actually was.</description></item><item><title>Drop and Give me 40 lines of code!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/drop-and-give-me-40-lines-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 16:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/drop-and-give-me-40-lines-of-code/</guid><description>Today we had a very interesting SCRUM meeting; Jason Alexander reassured us that we have a ton of work to do, and not a lot of time to get it done. The interns know that we all will prevail! He assigned everyone in pairs to do pair programming (Extreme Programming).
Towards the end of this meeting, Jason assigned me and Kevin to work together on the Reporting User Interface. All I could think was wow; we get to define how the User Interface is laid out.</description></item><item><title>Initial database design done</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/initial-database-design-done/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 15:43:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/initial-database-design-done/</guid><description>As always we started the day with meetings. Today, we finished up the initial database design portion and actually started making tables and merging the data together. I suspect that we will have at least one maybe two days left of just classifying and merging data.
There were several things that I learned today, most of it was MS SQL commands like (sp_who, sp_lock, sp_helptext, kill 60). It is always nice to see the commands in action and get a detailed explanation of what they return and do.</description></item><item><title>Rain, Rain, and more Rain</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/rain-rain-and-more-rain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 16:17:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/rain-rain-and-more-rain/</guid><description>We started today off with another scrum meeting. I already have it drilled into my head to go there automatically at 9:30am. Today, I did not spend too much time at the computer because we were in the VB conference room all day going over reporting and database design. Tomorrow we will finally be almost done with the database design layout portion. The only thing left is meeting with the SQL guru&amp;rsquo;s and talk about best practices and what would be the best way to accomplish our task.</description></item><item><title>More meetings and Sushi</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/more-meetings-and-sushi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2007 14:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/more-meetings-and-sushi/</guid><description>Today we had another Scrum meeting and another &amp;ldquo;Tattletale Design Session&amp;rdquo; that lasted for a few hours. We all had a lot of fun throwing even more ideas into what reports we can generate. I always liked the phrase &amp;ldquo;Design now, Code later&amp;rdquo;, and that is exactly what were doing. I sense that someone in the gang of interns has been really itching to code. Just give it time and we all will be eating, dreaming, and writing all sorts of code!</description></item><item><title>I am now an Telligent Intern!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/i-am-now-an-telligent-intern/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 18:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/i-am-now-an-telligent-intern/</guid><description>As some of you might be shocked that this is not a post about software releases and other such things. I have received an internship for this summer to work for Telligent Systems, Inc. They are located in Dallas, Texas. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what Telligent is, then you obviously haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the .net world long enough.
I arrived in Dallas, Texas on Sunday May 20th; it was a pretty short flight out of Wisconsin to Texas about three hours.</description></item><item><title>Meetings, lunch, and more meetings!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/meetings-lunch-and-more-meetings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 16:21:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/meetings-lunch-and-more-meetings/</guid><description>This morning I woke up ready for another day of learning anything and everything that I can get my hands on.
When we arrived at Telligent this morning, we all received an email stating that we would have scrum meetings everyday for the rest of the summer. So after the very short meeting about that dealt with the details of scrum development, we split paths and worked on individual tasks for about a half hour.</description></item><item><title>My first day at Telligent</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-first-day-at-telligent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 13:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/my-first-day-at-telligent/</guid><description>My first day at Telligent Systems, Inc. as intern has been pretty exciting! This morning all the interns listened to Jason Alexander as he gave us an orientation. He informed us with all the information we will would need to accomplish our goals while at Telligent Systems, Inc.
For all of you wondering what we interns will be working on this summer you will have to look no further. We will be working on a project codenamed Tattletale (Community Server Enterprise Reporting).</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Internet Explorer Developer Toolbar Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-internet-explorer-developer-toolbar-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 15:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-internet-explorer-developer-toolbar-released/</guid><description>For those of you who use the web developer add-on for Firefox. Then you might want spend the time and get your paws on this add-on for IE.
At PDC in 2005, we announced the Internet Explorer Developer Toolbar and made the first build available shortly after. Since then, we&amp;rsquo;ve released two additional betas; thanks to your testing and feedback, we&amp;rsquo;ve improved the quality and added new functionality like formatted source viewing and CSS selector matching.</description></item><item><title>MSDN Library April 2007 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/msdn-library-april-2007-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 22:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/msdn-library-april-2007-released/</guid><description>I just saw that the MSDN Library April 2007 was released. I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that an update has finally been released! It literally has been ages since they released it as a free download. The link is a direct download link as the page is not yet available. The file size is around 2.25GB.
MSDN Library provides access to essential programming information, including technical reference documentations, white papers, software development kits and code samples necessary to develop web services and applications.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft XML Notepad 2007 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-xml-notepad-2007-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 22:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-xml-notepad-2007-released/</guid><description>Lately it seems that Microsoft is really focused on pushing regular updates to its XML Notepad application. XML Notepad 2007 comes with even more improvements over the semi recent 2006 release.
Tree View synchronized with Node Text View for quick editing of node names and values. Incremental search (Ctrl+I) in both tree and text views, so as you type it navigates to matching nodes. Cut/copy/paste with full namespace support.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft to release FoxPro Sedna as Shared Source</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-to-release-foxpro-sedna-as-shared-source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 21:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-to-release-foxpro-sedna-as-shared-source/</guid><description>Mary Jo Foley whose currently in Seattle at the Microsoft MVP summit has learned that &amp;ldquo;Microsoft plans to release by the end of this summer the Foxpro &amp;ldquo;Sedna&amp;rdquo; bits as Shared Source on its CodePlex code-repository site&amp;rdquo;. For the complete article check out the source.
View Source Microsoft to release FoxPro &amp;lsquo;Sedna&amp;rsquo; as Shared Source</description></item><item><title>Important Daylight Savings Time Update for Microsoft .NET Framework Developers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/important-daylight-savings-time-update-for-microsoft-net-framework-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2007 00:19:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/important-daylight-savings-time-update-for-microsoft-net-framework-developers/</guid><description>A while back I received an email from Microsoft regarding a Daylight Saving Time (DST) update, which will take place via Windows Updates sometime soon. I highly recommend that everyone takes the time reads the below message even if this does not affect you, because it may help someone you know.
Dear Valued Microsoft Customer,
In 2005, the United States government passed the Energy Policy Act of 2005. This act changes the start and end dates for Daylight Saving Time (DST) as of spring 2007.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Service Pack 2 Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2005-service-pack-2-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 12:17:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-sql-server-2005-service-pack-2-released/</guid><description>Today Microsoft released SQL Server 2005 Service Pack 2. I personally have been waiting quite sometime for this update to come out as it fixes compatibility for Windows Vista. Hopefully we will not have to wait that long for Visual Studio 2005 service pack 1 for Windows Vista to be released.
View whats new in SQL Server 2005 Service Pack 2
Download SQL Server 2005 Service Pack 2</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2005 Keyboard Shortcut Reference Posters</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2005-keyboard-shortcut-reference-posters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 01:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2005-keyboard-shortcut-reference-posters/</guid><description>I found these posters after exploring an interesting MSDN blog of a K-12 Computer Science Academic Relations Manager. The posters are nice and well worth spending the couple of seconds to download them.
Here are the download links for each language(s) shortcut reference poster:
Visual Basic 2005 Visual C# Visual C++ Source Visual Studio Keyboard Shortcut Posters</description></item><item><title>Assembly Language Is FUN</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/assembly-language-is-fun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:52:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/assembly-language-is-fun/</guid><description>I started this semester with a bunch of classes. But the one I&amp;rsquo;m most passionate about is CPS 260 Assembly Language. Ever since I was about 12 I always wanted to learn assembly language. Now I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting that chance. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning ASM, you can buy this ASM book off Amazon like I did, which was around $80. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not the one to brag up a programming book as I have many on my shelf, but Assembly Language for Intel-Based Computers, Fifth Edition by Kip R.</description></item><item><title>USB Laser Guided Missile Launcher + API + Video surveillance with Motion Detection = FUN</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/usb-laser-guided-missile-launcher-api-video-surveillance-with-motion-detection-fun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:29:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/usb-laser-guided-missile-launcher-api-video-surveillance-with-motion-detection-fun/</guid><description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve had this plan of scaring anyone who comes near my computer while I&amp;rsquo;m in class.. Though this idea would only work once on the person walking by, it would still be quite hilarious to see.
So here is my idea&amp;hellip; Buy the USB Laser Guided Missile Launcher which comes with a set of API&amp;rsquo;s written in c#. I would then head to Wal-Mart and pick up a cheap web cam.</description></item><item><title>What Book Should I get?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-book-should-i-get/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-book-should-i-get/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering what book I should buy. I have narrowed it down to two categories Cryptography, or fractal. Please let me know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in Computer Cryptography and have read a book or two in the past on the subject. However this time around I want something current and fresh. Recently I remembered looking at fractal images in 9th grade, I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to sit down and create one.</description></item><item><title>Up and coming features in C# 3.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/up-and-coming-features-in-csharp-3.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 12:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/up-and-coming-features-in-csharp-3.0/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m personally looking forward to C# 3.0. There are some interesting new things coming to the language. However there are somethings I really don&amp;rsquo;t like about c# (please pay attention to the end of this video Anders Hejlsberg - Programming data in C# 3.0)
Local variable type inference (I personally don&amp;rsquo;t really like this idea) Extension Methods Lambda expressions Object initializers Collection initializers Query expressions Anonymous types Expression trees Automatic properties Source: C# 3.</description></item><item><title>Christmas 2006 News</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/christmas-2006-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 11:40:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/christmas-2006-news/</guid><description>I would like to inform everyone who reads these blogs, that during Christmas break; I will be releasing an update to FirefoxToIE7, an Office 2007 application, and three other stand alone applications. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get them out of the door. But its a little hectic with taking a full load in college and with exams.
I hope you all have a great christmas. -Blake</description></item><item><title>Slipstreaming Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/slipstreaming-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2006 11:15:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/slipstreaming-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</guid><description>Heath Stewart has made a nice how to on his MSDN blog on how to slipstream visual studio 2005 SP1. Its only a three step process to get everything up and working. Please make sure to read the notes at the bottom of the post for some valuable information.
Source Heath Stewart</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Releases Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 00:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1/</guid><description>Today, Microsoft released Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1 available for download immediately.
Service Pack 1 also provides over 70 improvements for common development scenarios including:
New processor support (e.g., Core Duo) for code generation and profiling Performance and scale improvements in Team Foundation Server* Team Foundation Server integration with Excel 2007 and Project 2007* Tool support for occasionally connected devices and SQL Server Compact Edition* Additional support for project file based Web applications* Windows Embedded 6.</description></item><item><title>A lesson in Color Theory for Developers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-lesson-in-color-theory-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 11:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-lesson-in-color-theory-for-developers/</guid><description>I read this article the other day and it struck me how often this happens. As a developer I sometimes find it hard to create even a decent looking GUI. Most of the time when developers through together a GUI it has 60 million check boxes on it and it does not look visually pleasing.
Color theory may sound like a subject for the Art Department, not for developers. But we&amp;rsquo;ve all had the experience of choosing a color scheme using the property grid to select named colors and ending up with a really garish color scheme.</description></item><item><title>Windows Presentation Foundation / Everywhere CTP is now Available</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/everywhere-ctp-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 13:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/everywhere-ctp-is-now-available/</guid><description>WPF/E is a way in which developers can deliver a rich user experience through the web browser. This content can be only accessed after a user downloads a browser plug-in, thankfully these plug-ins will work on Firefox, IE, and Safari. Microsoft has provided those who want to learn more about WPF/E with screencasts.
Source &amp;ldquo;WPF/E&amp;rdquo; is in the wild..</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Provides developers with free XP Professional Virtual Image</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-provides-developers-with-free-xp-professional-virtual-image/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 20:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-provides-developers-with-free-xp-professional-virtual-image/</guid><description>Microsoft knows the pain of web developers who have been trying to test their websites in both IE6 and IE7. For this reason Microsoft has released a Virtual Imaged pre-activated copy of Windows XP Professional that will stop working as of April 1st, 2007. This copy must be loaded in Virtual PC 2004 or 2007 which is a free download also. This will allow developers to install IE7 on there main machine and test there website in IE6 on a virtual Machine.</description></item><item><title>ASP.NET CSS Control Adapters RTM (Version 1.0)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-css-control-adapters-rtm-version-1.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 16:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-css-control-adapters-rtm-version-1.0/</guid><description>This is great new for designers and developers alike, and I&amp;rsquo;m really excited! With ASP.NET 1.x and ASP.NET 2.0, if you wanted to create pure CSS pages, it really wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. The ASP.NET controls would render with tables, inline styles and all sorts of other things that would make most web designers wince.
View change Log Change Log
Source ASP.NET CSS Control Adapters</description></item><item><title>Sun microsystems open sources Java!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/sun-microsystems-open-sources-java/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 10:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/sun-microsystems-open-sources-java/</guid><description>Sun microsystems this week submitted Java to two open source licenses the Common Development and Distribution License (CDDL), and the GPL v2 license. For more information please visit Sun Microsystems Project Overview located here (Free and Open Source Java Project Overview).</description></item><item><title>A white paper on how to make your Windows Vista application UAC friendly.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-white-paper-on-how-to-make-your-windows-vista-application-uac-friendly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 16:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/a-white-paper-on-how-to-make-your-windows-vista-application-uac-friendly/</guid><description>Microsoft has released a white paper pertaining on &amp;ldquo;how to develop UAC compliant applications for Windows Vista&amp;rdquo;, The following document contains the subjects or topics below.
This white paper includes details many aspects of designing and building applications that will work well with User Account Control (UAC) on Windows Vista.
At a high level, it describes the following steps to use when designing applications for Windows Vista:
Test Your Application for Application Compatibility Classify Your Application as a Standard User, Administrator, or Mixed User Application Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s Functionality for UAC Compatibility Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s User Interface for UAC Compatibility Redesign Your Application&amp;rsquo;s Installer Create and Embed an Application Manifest with Your Application Test Your Application Authenticode Sign Your Application Participate in the Windows Vista Logo Program In addition, it describes some interesting setup-specific considerations.</description></item><item><title>Free Visual Studio 2005 Add-In's</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/free-visual-studio-2005-add-ins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 18:33:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/free-visual-studio-2005-add-ins/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m just curious on the following subject, what other developers out there use Visual Studio 2005 Add-In&amp;rsquo;s. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see an Add-In that you currently use, please post a comment on the bottom of this post. Just click on the name of an Add-In below to view more information about it.
CoolCommands 3.0 SlickEdit - Gadgets There are ten more free Visual Studio 2005 Add-In&amp;rsquo;s listed and reviewed in the following article Visual Studio Add-Ins Every Developer Should Download Now</description></item><item><title>Microsoft RTM's .NET Framework 3.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-rtms-.net-framework-3.0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 01:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-rtms-.net-framework-3.0/</guid><description>Microsoft has now made the final version of .NET Framework 3.0, It is up for download on Microsoft downloads. Remember if your wanting to learn Windows Presentation Foundation for free then check out this post.
Some of the features that are included as follows:
Windows Communication Foundation Windows CardSpace Windows Presentation Foundation Windows Workflow Foundation You can download the full read me to the .NET Framework 3.0 here.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft RTM's Office 2007 and releases Visual Studio Tools for Office Second Edition</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-rtms-office-2007-and-releases-visual-studio-tools-for-office-second-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 17:38:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-rtms-office-2007-and-releases-visual-studio-tools-for-office-second-edition/</guid><description>This morning Microsoft RTM (Release to Manufacture) Office 2007 you can read the full details along with the information regarding how to get office 2007 retail version here. Be sure to visit the Microsoft Office Developer Center, for useful information about VSTO updates and news.
Watch the Demo of Visual Studio 2005 Tools for the 2007 Microsoft Office System, Second Edition
Download Microsoft Visual Studio 2005 Tools for the 2007 Microsoft Office System Source: Erika Ehrli</description></item><item><title>How to use Microsoft's Speech API (SAPI) in a managed application (C# - VB.Net)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsofts-speech-api-sapi-in-a-managed-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 15:55:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-use-microsofts-speech-api-sapi-in-a-managed-application/</guid><description>Sometime soon, I plan on releasing a cool application that uses text-to-speech. Some of you might have been curious about the implementation about text-to-speech for quite a while. The implementation of text-to-speech really isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard as long as you use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Speech API (SAPI). The current version of SAPI that you can download from Microsoft is 5.1, however if your running Windows Vista then you will have 5.3 preinstalled. If you have any version of Microsoft Office installed then you more then likely have this already, If not a download link is below.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Releases Windows Embedded CE 6.0 Plus Source Code</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-windows-embedded-ce-6.0-plus-source-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 13:20:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-windows-embedded-ce-6.0-plus-source-code/</guid><description>Microsoft officially launched Windows Embedded CE 6.0 today!, There are many improvements like: kernel enhancements, improved tools(Visual Studio 2005), and it is now 100% shared source.
View the Windows Embedded CE 6.0 Virtual Launch Event here
Download Windows Embedded CE 6.0 180 day evaluation Windows Embedded CE 6.0 Source Code</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Application Verifier Version 3.3</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-application-verifier-version-3.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 20:19:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-application-verifier-version-3.3/</guid><description>Application Verifier is a runtime verification tool for unmanaged code that assists in quickly finding subtle programming errors that can be extremely difficult to identify with normal application testing. Application Verifier is designed specifically to detect and help debug memory corruptions and critical security vulnerabilities. It makes it easier to create reliable applications by monitoring an application&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the Windows operating system, profiling its use of objects, the registry, the file system, and Win32 APIs (including heaps, handles, locks, and more).</description></item><item><title>ASP.Net Ajax Finally emerges!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-ajax-finally-emerges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 09:14:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-ajax-finally-emerges/</guid><description>Last month Scott Guthrie staid that &amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo; was going to have a new name, you can read more on that here.
Microsoft last night launched ASP.NET Ajax v1.0 Beta.
As one Microsoft employee stated &amp;ldquo;This is quite a significant jump in the product shipping cycle and brings it one step closer to being released with out any &amp;lsquo;CTP&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Beta&amp;rsquo; suffix!&amp;rdquo; Mark Johnston
For more information on ASP.NET Ajax and how to download it, please visit ajax.</description></item><item><title>How to make a UI "smarter"</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-make-a-ui-smarter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 16:48:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-make-a-ui-smarter/</guid><description>First off, I would like to clarify how bad I am at making UI&amp;rsquo;s (User Interfaces). It never has been my specialty, but I know when I come across a UI that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been thought out for the consumers needs. Since I&amp;rsquo;m a gamer I&amp;rsquo;d like to show you a UI from (Valve Software) that I really am disgusted with, but am forced to use it.
If you notice, that none of the filters are filled in and everything is being displayed correctly.</description></item><item><title>Are your applications ready for Windows Vista?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/are-your-applications-ready-for-windows-vista/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/are-your-applications-ready-for-windows-vista/</guid><description>The last beta build of Windows Vista has been released to the public. If you&amp;rsquo;re developing any applications where your intended audience will be using Windows Vista, then this is the time to download Windows Vista before it goes RTM (Released to Manufactures). Any applications that run on Vista RC1/RC2 (Release Candidate), will be certain to work with the RTM version that&amp;rsquo;s expected to be released very soon.
Some of the cool things to check out once you have Windows Vista up and running is the following: IIS7, .</description></item><item><title>Do you know Windows Forms? Then why not Learn WPF</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/do-you-know-windows-forms-then-why-not-learn-wpf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2006 09:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/do-you-know-windows-forms-then-why-not-learn-wpf/</guid><description>I came across this article this morning off of one of my saved feeds from blogs.msdn.com, If are wanting to learn WPF (Windows Presentation Foundation) and you have already know how to develop Windows Forms. Then you are in luck, Microsoft has created a document (&amp;ldquo;WPF for those who know Windows Forms&amp;rdquo;) to help everyone willing to make the transition.
Download WPF for those who know Windows Forms</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1 Beta Has started</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1-beta-has-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 15:25:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1-beta-has-started/</guid><description>Microsoft will be starting shortly a beta release of Service Pack 1 (sp1) for Visual Studio 2005. As of right now Microsoft is currently gathering and processing bug reports and user suggestions, which will be incorporated into SP1.</description></item><item><title>10 Programming Languages everyone should learn.</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/10-programming-languages-everyone-should-learn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/10-programming-languages-everyone-should-learn/</guid><description>I found this over at eweek.com a few days ago and found it to be worthy of posting.
1. PHP What it is: An open-source, interpretive, server-side, cross-platform, HTML scripting language, especially well-suited for Web development as it can be embedded into HTML pages. Why you should learn it: It&amp;rsquo;s particularly widely used. &amp;ldquo;High-speed scripting with caching, augmented with compiled code plug-ins (such as can be done with Perl and PHP) is where the future is.</description></item><item><title>Atlas gets a new name!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/atlas-gets-a-new-name/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 09:57:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/atlas-gets-a-new-name/</guid><description>Of the product names that we will begin using moving forward. What was formerly called &amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo; will now have a few names:
The client-side &amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo; javascript library is going to be called the Microsoft AJAX Library. This will work with any browser, and also support any backend web server (read these blog post to see how to run it on ColdFusion). The server-side &amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo; functionality that nicely integrates with ASP.</description></item><item><title>XML Notepad 2006</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/xml-notepad-2006/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 00:55:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/xml-notepad-2006/</guid><description>Microsoft has recently released an xml tool, strangely enough its not called &amp;lsquo;Windows Live XML Notepad 2006&amp;rsquo;. It is a pretty useful application if your needing a lightweight xml editor and don&amp;rsquo;t wish to use notepad2 etc.
Jeff from windowsconnected.com has written a nice review on &amp;lsquo;Xml Notepad 2006&amp;rsquo; with pictures on his blog located here.
Download here</description></item><item><title>Firefox To IE7" and Windows Vista RC1</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/firefox-to-ie7-and-windows-vista-rc1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2006 02:18:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/firefox-to-ie7-and-windows-vista-rc1/</guid><description>If your getting a bookmarks.html does not appear to be a valid firefox document. when using &amp;ldquo;Firefox To IE7&amp;rdquo; in Windows Vista RC1 or newer its due to the File IO Permissions and UAC. To fix this right click FireFox To IE7.exe and select Run as Administrator and everything should now work.</description></item><item><title>Creating your very own Windows Live Gadget</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/creating-your-very-own-windows-live-gadget/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2006 21:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/creating-your-very-own-windows-live-gadget/</guid><description>When you plan on working with any Windows Live technology, the best place to stop first is dev.live.com. There is a very nice step by step tutorial located here that will show you how to make a Windows Live Gadget step by step with code samples.
After you get done creating your gadget the best thing to do would be to open it up with drip to detect memory leaks. On the bottom of drips website there are 5 links that you can view that will get you up to date on how to fix your code and find memory leaks.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio .Net 2003 Service Pack 1 Released!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2003-service-pack-1-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 21:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/visual-studio-2003-service-pack-1-released/</guid><description>Microsoft has released SP1 for Visual Studio .Net 2003. If you&amp;rsquo;re developing .Net 1.1 applications then I highly recommend installing vs2003 SP1 now.
Download here</description></item><item><title>Adding ActiveX to your Windows Sidebar Gadgets: A Pictorial Tutorial</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/adding-activex-to-your-windows-sidebar-gadgets-a-pictorial-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 10:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/adding-activex-to-your-windows-sidebar-gadgets-a-pictorial-tutorial/</guid><description>Bruce Williams has taken the time to write up a three part tutorial with pictures on how to create and deploy a basic gadget using ActiveX and C++. You would want to use ActiveX in your gadget to access anything that&amp;rsquo;s not currently implemented in the gadget API&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Phalanger the new .Net Web Language. Welcome php.net!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/phalanger-the-new-.net-web-language-welcome-php.net/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2006 16:11:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/phalanger-the-new-.net-web-language-welcome-php.net/</guid><description>I really haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time lately to do very much, but I came across this interesting bit of news about the ability of php to run on the .Net Framework. Apparently they phpbb forums running on the .Net framework and that is really amazing. Below is a quote describing what Phalanger really is.
Phalanger is a new PHP implementation introducing the PHP language into the family of compiled .</description></item><item><title>CSS optimization application review</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/css-optimization-application-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2006 14:21:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/css-optimization-application-review/</guid><description>David from bloggingpro wrote up an interesting article that compares four different CSS optimization products (CSS Optimizer, Icey&amp;rsquo;s CSS Compressor, Flumpcakes CSS Optimizer, and CleanCSS).
Even though you might not think that CSS Optimization is not that important. But it could mean the difference of 1 or 2 seconds for high-speed users or up to 5 or more seconds for dial-up users.
Here are the results of his tests on five different sites ( digg.</description></item><item><title>Were you considering adding Windows Contact integration into your application?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/were-you-considering-adding-windows-contact-integration-into-your-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 19:59:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/were-you-considering-adding-windows-contact-integration-into-your-application/</guid><description>If you are thinking about adding any Windows Contact features into your managed application you might want to think again. Currently there is no managed wrapper for the C\C++ API that is currently documented on MSDN.
However, if you wish to read a windows contact file into your application you&amp;rsquo;re in luck. The .Contact file is an XML document; Microsoft has released the Windows Contact Schema Element Definitions on MSDN for this XML document type.</description></item><item><title>AJAX + Java = Great|Not so great|?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/ajax-java-great-not-so-great/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2006 07:35:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/ajax-java-great-not-so-great/</guid><description>For those of you who are writing java applications. I came across this article this morning about using Ajax and java together. I wish I had the time to work with java and add Ajax into my application, and let everyone know how this works before posting this article but that&amp;rsquo;s just not possible.
So if you are a java developer and have already implemented Ajax into your application; Please Let us know what you think.</description></item><item><title>Why every web developer should embrace rel="nofollow"</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/why-every-web-developer-should-embrace-rel-nofollow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 11:28:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/why-every-web-developer-should-embrace-rel-nofollow/</guid><description>Today a developer who I recently met, showed me the importance of rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot;. He pointed me out to an article that explained how rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; works. It is so important in a way to reduce spam that Google, MSN and Yahoo search have now implemented rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;rdquo; into the way their search engines operate.</description></item><item><title>What is the best text editor for editing a single file?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-is-the-best-text-editor-for-editing-a-single-file/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2006 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/what-is-the-best-text-editor-for-editing-a-single-file/</guid><description>I was wondering what other developers like to use for general editing of a single text file (VB, C#, XML, HTML, etc). I personally prefer notepad or notepad2. Every now and then I will use Visual Studio if I feel like killing some system resources.</description></item><item><title>ASP.NET Atlas July 2006 Community Technology Preview (CTP)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-atlas-july-2006-community-technology-preview-ctp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 16:55:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/asp.net-atlas-july-2006-community-technology-preview-ctp/</guid><description>A new Community Technology Preview of Atlas has been released on the atlas website atlas.asp.net.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Debugging Tools for Windows x86 and x64 Platforms</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-debugging-tools-for-windows-x86-and-x64-platforms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 19:34:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-debugging-tools-for-windows-x86-and-x64-platforms/</guid><description>The current version of Microsoft Debugging Tools is 6.6.7.5 and was released on July 18, 2006; For more information read the relnotes.txt after you have installed the application.
Overview Debugging Tools for Windows contains tools to analyze and debug Windows, Windows drivers, and applications. It can analyze memory dump files or perform live debugging.
The kernel debugger is KD.exe. It can be installed and run on all the platforms listed below.</description></item><item><title>MSDN Libraries are now FREE!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/msdn-libraries-are-now-free/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2006 10:23:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/msdn-libraries-are-now-free/</guid><description>According to Rob Caron&amp;rsquo;s blog, The current May MSDN Library and future MSDN Libraries will be freely available to anyone one on the Microsoft Downloads website. This is really great news for developers out there who don&amp;rsquo;t have the money to purchase a MSDN Subscription.
Click here to download the May 2006 MSDN Library.</description></item><item><title>Convert your firefox favorites and feeds into IE7 with "Firefox To IE7"</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/convert-your-firefox-favorites-and-feeds-into-ie7-with-firefox-to-ie7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 19:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/convert-your-firefox-favorites-and-feeds-into-ie7-with-firefox-to-ie7/</guid><description>Currently there is no way to import your firefox favorites and feeds into IE7, and from what I have heard there is no plan on adding this into IE7. So with this in mind, I made this application so that developers or anyone who needs to use their firefox bookmarks in IE7 can do so easily.
All you have to do is run the application and if you have firefox installed it will automatically find your bookmarks, or you can browse for your exported firefox “bookmarks.</description></item><item><title>Working with the Microsoft Windows RSS Platform (C#)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/working-with-the-microsoft-windows-rss-platform-csharp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 05:24:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/working-with-the-microsoft-windows-rss-platform-csharp/</guid><description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what RSS is, then you have been hiding under a pretty big rock lately. A lot of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s products are currently out or are coming out in the next year use the Windows RSS platform. To name a few of these products off the top of my head are as follows: IE7, Office 2007, Windows Live Mail Desktop, and Windows Vista. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that sometime in the next couple of years you will more than likely be working with RSS in one or more of your applications.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1 Update for Windows Vista Released</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1-update-for-windows-vista-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 00:53:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2005-service-pack-1-update-for-windows-vista-released/</guid><description>Microsoft earlier today released an Visual Studio 2005 SP1 patch that fixes certain application compatibility problems when running Visual Studio 2005 on Windows Vista.
Download Visual Studio 2005 Service Pack 1 Update for Windows Vista</description></item><item><title>How-to: Rename your generated CSLA properties</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-rename-your-generated-csla-properties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-rename-your-generated-csla-properties/</guid><description>In the following example, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use the CodeSmith Generator CSLA template&amp;rsquo;s powerful renaming options. Many of you might have a legacy database with those ugly prefixes, or things you wish you could refactor but just can&amp;rsquo;t. Luckily, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck as CodeSmith Generator is going to save the day once again! By default we will strip any invalid characters from your property names like prefixed digits etc&amp;hellip; Please note that these methods also work for renaming class names, but there are other methods that we will cover later that are is the recommended way to specify a class name.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Upgrade your existing CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates from version 3.8 to 4.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-codesmith-generator-csla-templates-from-version-3.8-to-4.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-codesmith-generator-csla-templates-from-version-3.8-to-4.0/</guid><description>We recently released a new major version of the CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates that add support for many new features including Visual Studio 2010, CSLA 4.0 and Silverlight 4.0 support. They can be downloaded here. When upgrading to the templates and you are going from CSLA 3.8 to the latest CSLA 3.8.4 templates, there really aren&amp;rsquo;t any changes you need to make other than updating your CodeSmith Project File template location to point to the new version of the templates.</description></item></channel></rss>