<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Automation on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/home-automation/</link><description>Recent content in Home Automation on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 09:39:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/home-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at North Dallas Developers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-north-dallas-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 09:39:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-north-dallas-developers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at North Dallas Developers on Building and maintaining a smart home on August 5, 2020 at 6:30 PM Central Standard Time.
Visit the link above to RSVP to the virtual talk.
Overview I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering my experiences building and maintaining a smart home. Starting from nothing to having a fully automated house can be overwhelming. We’ll cover many topics like choosing future proof products (usability, security, etc.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Using NFC Tags to trigger device or home automations</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-using-nfc-tags-to-trigger-device-or-home-automation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-using-nfc-tags-to-trigger-device-or-home-automation/</guid><description>This post will cover how I use NFC tags with Home Assistant to trigger automations. I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out all the information below on how you can use NFC Tags to automate other apps and devices as well!
I really like using Near Field Communication (NFC) for home or device based automations because it is really cheap and the possibilities are endless as you can place them in any environmental condition and on almost any physical object.</description></item><item><title>How-to normalize home volume levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>This post is going to cover normalizing all media_player volume levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend reading my previous blog post on sending Text-to-Speech notifications which dives a bit deeper on the optional accessibility Subflow this Flow consumes.
This automation normalizes all volume levels in my home based on the time of day using the Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to bring in all my Amazon Echo and ecobee Switch+ devices into Home Assistant.</description></item><item><title>How-to send Text-to-Speech notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:35:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to send Text-to-Speech (TTS) notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED? In the sections below I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to send TTS notifications. Please note you can easily switch out the TTS integration to the one of your choosing and still use this Subflow (with a few tweaks).
This is one of my favorite Subflows as it can be used easily in a lot of automations.</description></item><item><title>Let's talk about smart home accessibility</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</guid><description>I define accessibility as a critical necessity to be inclusive to everyone. No matter how big or small the task, anyone should be able complete the task at hand regardless of the disability (e.g., vision, hearing, mobility, device access, language, etc).
You might be wondering what does this have to do with smart homes and why should I think or care about this? I think there are a few simple facts to consider:</description></item><item><title>Installing Home Assistant on Ubuntu</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 02:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>NOTE: This post has been updated on May 26th to use Docker-CE instead of Snap.
Home Assistant has stated they will no longer support this installation method but there currently is no other way to use external storage.
I recently upgraded my Home Assistant server to an Intel NUC 10 Performance Kit (NUC10i7FNH) from an Atomic Pi. I needed to manually install and configure Ubuntu on my hardware there is an issue where you cannot boot from the NVMe drive.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Home Assistant hardware in 2020</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded or swapped my Home Assistant hardware more times than I want to count. I want to share the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way when choosing hardware to run Home Assistant locally. I always try choose hardware is lower power and will take up limited space in my 9U Server Cabinet
Skip to March 2020 for a summary of what I recently upgraded to and the Conclusion if you are looking for current hardware recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about smart home power usage</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a great deal of my life admiring nature and thinking of ways we can do to reduce our footprint. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve taken steps both physically and monetarily to do so.
The Dreaded Power Bill Which is why one Wisconsin Winter day I opened my utility (gas and electric) bill and had a not so pleasant moment. Complete sticker shock at the $410 USD single month total, which was our highest bill yet.</description></item><item><title>Hello Home Automation, How-to detect battery levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start off 2020 by converting my blog to Hugo and start blogging again! This is my first of many posts on home automation! This post is going to cover generically detecting battery levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED.
TLDR: Use the Function node defined in the Node-RED snippet here to properly handle all the edge cases.
I decided to share my experiences based on seeing what others were doing in this thread.</description></item></channel></rss>