<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Audio on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/audio/</link><description>Recent content in Audio on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 08:11:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How-to normalize home volume levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-normalize-home-volume-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>This post is going to cover normalizing all media_player volume levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend reading my previous blog post on sending Text-to-Speech notifications which dives a bit deeper on the optional accessibility Subflow this Flow consumes.
This automation normalizes all volume levels in my home based on the time of day using the Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to bring in all my Amazon Echo and ecobee Switch+ devices into Home Assistant.</description></item><item><title>How-to send Text-to-Speech notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:35:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-send-text-to-speech-notifications-with-home-assistant-and-node-red/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to send Text-to-Speech (TTS) notifications with Home Assistant and Node-RED? In the sections below I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using Amazon Alexa Media Player Integration to send TTS notifications. Please note you can easily switch out the TTS integration to the one of your choosing and still use this Subflow (with a few tweaks).
This is one of my favorite Subflows as it can be used easily in a lot of automations.</description></item></channel></rss>