<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry Pi on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 09:12:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing smart home devices with ESPHome</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/securing-smart-home-devices-with-esphome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 09:12:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/securing-smart-home-devices-with-esphome/</guid><description>When I first came across the ESPHome project a year or so ago. I thought it was interesting and something that I would use if I was building a smart device from scratch. I thought of all the things I could do, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the idea of all the maintenance I could foresee.
ESPHome is a system to control your ESP8266/ESP32 by simple yet powerful configuration files and control them remotely through Home Automation systems.</description></item><item><title>Installing Home Assistant on Ubuntu</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 02:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>NOTE: This post has been updated on May 26th to use Docker-CE instead of Snap.
Home Assistant has stated they will no longer support this installation method but there currently is no other way to use external storage.
I recently upgraded my Home Assistant server to an Intel NUC 10 Performance Kit (NUC10i7FNH) from an Atomic Pi. I needed to manually install and configure Ubuntu on my hardware there is an issue where you cannot boot from the NVMe drive.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Home Assistant hardware in 2020</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded or swapped my Home Assistant hardware more times than I want to count. I want to share the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way when choosing hardware to run Home Assistant locally. I always try choose hardware is lower power and will take up limited space in my 9U Server Cabinet
Skip to March 2020 for a summary of what I recently upgraded to and the Conclusion if you are looking for current hardware recommendations.</description></item></channel></rss>