<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart Home on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/smart-home/</link><description>Recent content in Smart Home on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 09:12:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/smart-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing smart home devices with ESPHome</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/securing-smart-home-devices-with-esphome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 09:12:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/securing-smart-home-devices-with-esphome/</guid><description>When I first came across the ESPHome project a year or so ago. I thought it was interesting and something that I would use if I was building a smart device from scratch. I thought of all the things I could do, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the idea of all the maintenance I could foresee.
ESPHome is a system to control your ESP8266/ESP32 by simple yet powerful configuration files and control them remotely through Home Automation systems.</description></item><item><title>Building and maintaining a smart home presentation</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/building-and-maintaining-a-smart-home-presentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/building-and-maintaining-a-smart-home-presentation/</guid><description>Here is a recent recording of a new talk I recently gave at North Dallas Developers on my experiences building and maintaining a smart home.
Here is a high level overview of what is covered in the presentation:
First Steps What are your Goals? Existing products and ecosystems Research Future technologies Are you the product? How-to choose a contractor Costs Accessibility Breaking Changes Companies will break you or sell your data Smart Home Hubs Automations Feedback Any feedback is greatly appreciated on how I can improve this talk.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about smart home power usage</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/thinking-about-smart-home-power-usage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a great deal of my life admiring nature and thinking of ways we can do to reduce our footprint. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve taken steps both physically and monetarily to do so.
The Dreaded Power Bill Which is why one Wisconsin Winter day I opened my utility (gas and electric) bill and had a not so pleasant moment. Complete sticker shock at the $410 USD single month total, which was our highest bill yet.</description></item><item><title>Hello Home Automation, How-to detect battery levels with Node-RED</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/hello-home-automation-how-to-detect-battery-levels-with-node-red/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start off 2020 by converting my blog to Hugo and start blogging again! This is my first of many posts on home automation! This post is going to cover generically detecting battery levels with Home Assistant and Node-RED.
TLDR: Use the Function node defined in the Node-RED snippet here to properly handle all the edge cases.
I decided to share my experiences based on seeing what others were doing in this thread.</description></item></channel></rss>