<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RSS on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/rss/</link><description>Recent content in RSS on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 19:08:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/rss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convert your firefox favorites and feeds into IE7 with "Firefox To IE7"</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/convert-your-firefox-favorites-and-feeds-into-ie7-with-firefox-to-ie7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 19:08:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/convert-your-firefox-favorites-and-feeds-into-ie7-with-firefox-to-ie7/</guid><description>Currently there is no way to import your firefox favorites and feeds into IE7, and from what I have heard there is no plan on adding this into IE7. So with this in mind, I made this application so that developers or anyone who needs to use their firefox bookmarks in IE7 can do so easily.
All you have to do is run the application and if you have firefox installed it will automatically find your bookmarks, or you can browse for your exported firefox “bookmarks.</description></item><item><title>Working with the Microsoft Windows RSS Platform (C#)</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/working-with-the-microsoft-windows-rss-platform-csharp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 05:24:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/working-with-the-microsoft-windows-rss-platform-csharp/</guid><description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what RSS is, then you have been hiding under a pretty big rock lately. A lot of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s products are currently out or are coming out in the next year use the Windows RSS platform. To name a few of these products off the top of my head are as follows: IE7, Office 2007, Windows Live Mail Desktop, and Windows Vista. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that sometime in the next couple of years you will more than likely be working with RSS in one or more of your applications.</description></item></channel></rss>