<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Accessibility on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/accessibility/</link><description>Recent content in Accessibility on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/accessibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building and maintaining a smart home presentation</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/building-and-maintaining-a-smart-home-presentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/building-and-maintaining-a-smart-home-presentation/</guid><description>Here is a recent recording of a new talk I recently gave at North Dallas Developers on my experiences building and maintaining a smart home.
Here is a high level overview of what is covered in the presentation:
First Steps What are your Goals? Existing products and ecosystems Research Future technologies Are you the product? How-to choose a contractor Costs Accessibility Breaking Changes Companies will break you or sell your data Smart Home Hubs Automations Feedback Any feedback is greatly appreciated on how I can improve this talk.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at North Dallas Developers</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-north-dallas-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 09:39:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/speaking-at-north-dallas-developers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk at North Dallas Developers on Building and maintaining a smart home on August 5, 2020 at 6:30 PM Central Standard Time.
Visit the link above to RSVP to the virtual talk.
Overview I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering my experiences building and maintaining a smart home. Starting from nothing to having a fully automated house can be overwhelming. We’ll cover many topics like choosing future proof products (usability, security, etc.</description></item><item><title>Let's talk about smart home accessibility</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/lets-talk-about-smart-home-accessibility/</guid><description>I define accessibility as a critical necessity to be inclusive to everyone. No matter how big or small the task, anyone should be able complete the task at hand regardless of the disability (e.g., vision, hearing, mobility, device access, language, etc).
You might be wondering what does this have to do with smart homes and why should I think or care about this? I think there are a few simple facts to consider:</description></item></channel></rss>