<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Assistant on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/home-assistant/</link><description>Recent content in Home Assistant on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 08:11:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/categories/home-assistant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How-to: Using NFC Tags to trigger device or home automations</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-using-nfc-tags-to-trigger-device-or-home-automation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-using-nfc-tags-to-trigger-device-or-home-automation/</guid><description>This post will cover how I use NFC tags with Home Assistant to trigger automations. I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out all the information below on how you can use NFC Tags to automate other apps and devices as well!
I really like using Near Field Communication (NFC) for home or device based automations because it is really cheap and the possibilities are endless as you can place them in any environmental condition and on almost any physical object.</description></item><item><title>Installing Home Assistant on Ubuntu</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 02:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/installing-home-assistant-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>NOTE: This post has been updated on May 26th to use Docker-CE instead of Snap.
Home Assistant has stated they will no longer support this installation method but there currently is no other way to use external storage.
I recently upgraded my Home Assistant server to an Intel NUC 10 Performance Kit (NUC10i7FNH) from an Atomic Pi. I needed to manually install and configure Ubuntu on my hardware there is an issue where you cannot boot from the NVMe drive.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Home Assistant hardware in 2020</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/upgrading-home-assistant-hardware-in-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded or swapped my Home Assistant hardware more times than I want to count. I want to share the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way when choosing hardware to run Home Assistant locally. I always try choose hardware is lower power and will take up limited space in my 9U Server Cabinet
Skip to March 2020 for a summary of what I recently upgraded to and the Conclusion if you are looking for current hardware recommendations.</description></item></channel></rss>