<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Silverlight on Blake Niemyjski</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/silverlight/</link><description>Recent content in Silverlight on Blake Niemyjski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 17:39:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeniemyjski.com/tags/silverlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginning Silverlight 4 in C#</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/beginning-silverlight-4-in-csharp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 17:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/beginning-silverlight-4-in-csharp/</guid><description>I have read many technical books over the years and this is one is one of those books that you know you better keep handy. I really like how Robert has this book laid out and how he introduces you to Silverlight. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a .NET guy since version 1.0. But like most developers, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to really dive into Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s latest technologies like Silverlight until they have a few versions released.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Windows Live Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-live-tools-for-microsoft-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 18:02:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-windows-live-tools-for-microsoft-visual-studio/</guid><description>Windows Live™ Tools for Microsoft® Visual Studio® 2008 are a set of control add-ins to make incorporating Windows Live services into your Web application easier with Visual Studio 2008 and Visual Web Developer Express 2008.
Download the Community Technical Preview of Windows Live Tools for Microsoft Visual Studio Now
The six controls included in this CTP release are: Contacts Control (reference) IDLoginStatus Control (reference)* IDLoginView Control (reference)* MessengerChat Control (reference)* SilverlightStreamingMediaPlayer Control (reference)* Map Control (reference)* Requirements for Using Windows Live Tools This CTP release only targets English (United States).</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Silverlight 2.0 is almost here!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-silverlight-2.0-is-almost-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 14:18:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-silverlight-2.0-is-almost-here/</guid><description>Over the past week there has been some talk on Scott Guthrie and Shawn Burke blog about Silverlight 2.0. Please check out Scott&amp;rsquo;s blog for included features and eight walk through pertaining to Silverlight 2.0, and Shawn&amp;rsquo;s for more information on what we can expect while developing Silverlight 2.0 enabled applications.
Continue reading Scott Guthrie&amp;rsquo;s blog: First Look at Silverlight 2
Continue reading Shawn Burke&amp;rsquo;s blog: Getting to know Silverlight 2.</description></item><item><title>Got .NET Posters?</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/got-dot-net-posters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 12:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/got-dot-net-posters/</guid><description>Chris Bowen&amp;rsquo;s did a search last month for all posters available on Microsoft Downloads. This is what he found:
.NET 3.5 Namespaces Poster The .NET Framework 3.5 Common Namespaces and Types Poster
Visual Basic 2008 Keybinding Poster Printable wall poster containing list of useful keyboard shortcuts for Visual Basic 2008 developers
Visual C++ 2008 Keybinding Poster List of keybindings for Visual C++ language within Visual Studio and Visual C++ Express 2008</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 related downloads</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-related-downloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 09:06:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-visual-studio-2008-related-downloads/</guid><description>The last couple of days have been better than Christmas for a few of us. Microsoft has been releasing many updates to its developer tools and sdk to go with the recent release of Visual Studio 2008. Below I have listed the updates that have been released with download links. Enjoy!
Visual Studio 2008 Download Express Versions here Download Retail Versions (MSDN subscribers only) here Download Trial Versions here Visual Studio 2008 SDK This is the official software development kit that allows developers to integrate tools, editors, designers, languages, and other features inside Visual Studio 2008.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft offers four free GBs of Silverlight hosting!</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-offers-four-free-gbs-of-silverlight-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 16:09:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-offers-four-free-gbs-of-silverlight-hosting/</guid><description>Microsoft is offering four GBs of hosting space to anyone needing a place to host there Silverlight applications. I just hope a lot of people will see the importance in the stance Microsoft is taking on this subject. So what are you waiting for? Go and get yourself some free hosting.
Microsoft® Silverlight™ Streaming by Windows Live™ is a companion service for Silverlight that makes it easier for developers and designers to deliver and scale rich media as part of their Silverlight applications.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft releases Silverlight 1.0 RTM</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-silverlight-1.0-rtm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 07:26:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/microsoft-releases-silverlight-1.0-rtm/</guid><description>Last night Microsoft released version 1.0 of Silverlight. Silverlight is a very new and exciting product that will change the way we see the web.
Compelling Cross-Platform User Experiences Deliver media experiences and rich interactive applications for the Web that incorporate video, animation, interactivity and stunning user interfaces.
Seamless, fast installation for users, thanks to a small, on-demand, easy-to-install plug-in that is under 2 megabytes (MB) in size and works with all leading browsers.</description></item><item><title>How-to: Upgrade your existing CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates from version 3.8 to 4.0</title><link>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-codesmith-generator-csla-templates-from-version-3.8-to-4.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blakeniemyjski.com/blog/how-to-upgrade-your-existing-codesmith-generator-csla-templates-from-version-3.8-to-4.0/</guid><description>We recently released a new major version of the CodeSmith Generator CSLA templates that add support for many new features including Visual Studio 2010, CSLA 4.0 and Silverlight 4.0 support. They can be downloaded here. When upgrading to the templates and you are going from CSLA 3.8 to the latest CSLA 3.8.4 templates, there really aren&amp;rsquo;t any changes you need to make other than updating your CodeSmith Project File template location to point to the new version of the templates.</description></item></channel></rss>